<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>neidetcher.com</title>
 <link href="http://neidetcher.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://neidetcher.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-05-13T19:59:56-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://neidetcher.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Demian Neidetcher</name>
   <email>demian0311@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Just Enough Rrdtool</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2014/05/13/just-enough-rrdtool.html"/>
   <updated>2014-05-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2014/05/13/just-enough-rrdtool</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;DevOps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get into devops you will run into &lt;a href=&quot;http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/&quot;&gt;RRDB&lt;/a&gt;.  RRDB stands
for Round Robin DataBase.  It&amp;#39;s a file that you set up with a fixed size based on 
what you tell it you want to store and how you want to retain that information.  The
consistent file size is important because even if the system you&amp;#39;re tracking runs out of
disk space, your RRDB won&amp;#39;t ask for more room.  The tooling around it doesn&amp;#39;t use temp 
files or anything so your monitoring will all continue to work.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work some of my more motivated co-workers have stood up an instance of &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphite.wikidot.com/&quot;&gt;Graphite&lt;/a&gt;.  Graphite
leverages RRDB to accept monitoring information and turn it into data and graphs that you can
render based on what you want to see.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;#39;ve been working on a talk that I&amp;#39;ve been giving that touches on devops.  In the talk I 
have live demos for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circuit_breaker_design_pattern&quot;&gt;Circuit Breakers&lt;/a&gt; (using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/Hystrix&quot;&gt;Hystrix&lt;/a&gt; project from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netflix.com/&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;).  But
I didn&amp;#39;t have a compelling demonstration on how to turn data, logs or metrics into graphs.  Graphite 
and other tooling seemed too heavy for a little demo during a talk.  That and I 
thought it&amp;#39;d be too heavy-weight for someone to play with right away.  So I decided to use
simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/&quot;&gt;RRDtool&lt;/a&gt; to work with RRDB files in a shell script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll refine my use of RRDB later to do something live on a local system.  But I wanted something
that was gathering real data from a running system to show off.  That way I didn&amp;#39;t have to 
think about how to create synthetic data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My Little Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My site is running on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com/&quot;&gt;RackSpace&lt;/a&gt; virtual machine.  My web server is &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.nginx.org/Main&quot;&gt;NGINX&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;#39;m going to show
how to get &lt;em&gt;very rough&lt;/em&gt; information out of my NGINX logs and turn that into pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/demian0311/fc5b45cc901d36889b5e&quot;&gt;full script in a gist&lt;/a&gt; but we&amp;#39;ll walk through each section of a shell script.  It seemed
to make sense to me to put all these things together in one
script.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we just define variables.
&lt;code&gt;
name=neidetcher_access
rrdfile=&amp;quot;/var/local/${name}.rrd&amp;quot;
imageDir=&amp;quot;/home/demian/code/demian0311.github.com/_site&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Create an RRDB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you get going you need to set up an RRDB.  The &lt;code&gt;--step 60&lt;/code&gt; says 
we want to store things in 60 second increments.  We also tell it about
a data source that&amp;#39;s a GAUGE.  If anything comes in after 120 seconds then
we want to discard it.  And good values will be between 0 and 1000000.  We
also say that we want to keep around an average of the last hour and an
average of the last 24 hours.  rrdtool will take care of averaging all the
updates it gets into nice averages that we can later graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;rrdtool create $rrdfile --step 60 \
   &amp;quot;DS:${name}:GAUGE:120:0:1000000&amp;quot; \
   &amp;quot;RRA:AVERAGE:0:1:60&amp;quot; \
   &amp;quot;RRA:AVERAGE:0:60:24&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to do this step in my script I would run this one time to set things up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;root@raven:~/bin# ./neidetcher_access_log.sh create
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Logtail &amp;amp; rrdtool update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we use logtail.  I have to admit up until 6 months ago I didn&amp;#39;t even 
know logtail was a thing but it&amp;#39;s pretty cool.  It reads a log file and 
keeps track of how far it got last time.  Then the next time you run it,
it&amp;#39;ll start from that position.  It has smarts like knowing what the 
inode is of the file.  So if the file has been replaced it&amp;#39;ll start over
at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we just get a line count wich roughly correlates to the number of 
requests that came into NGINx.  We get that for two log files, add them
together and shove that value into our RRDB using &lt;a href=&quot;http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/&quot;&gt;rrdtool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;http_value=`/usr/sbin/logtail -f /var/log/nginx/neidetcher.access.log \
   -o /var/log/nginx/.neidetcher.access.log.offset | wc -l`
https_value=`/usr/sbin/logtail -f /var/log/nginx/ssl_neidetcher.access.log \
   -o /var/log/nginx/.ssl_neidetcher.access.log.offset| wc -l`
value=$(($http_value + $https_value))

rrdtool update $rrdfile N:${value}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That capability runs once a minute from cron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;* * * * * /root/bin/neidetcher_access_log.sh update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;rrdtool graph&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the fun part where we graph the data that we&amp;#39;ve been tracking.  The
first time we get 1 hour worth, the second time we get 24 hours worth.
We move that file into where all my static HTML is for my site and that&amp;#39;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;rrdtool graph ./${name}_hour.png \
         --start end-1h \
         DEF:${name}=${rrdfile}:${name}:AVERAGE \
         AREA:${name}#aa5555:${name}
mv -f ./${name}_hour.png ${imageDir}/${name}_hour.png

rrdtool graph ./${name}_day.png \
         --start end-24h \
         DEF:${name}=${rrdfile}:${name}:AVERAGE \
         AREA:${name}#aa5555:${name}
mv -f ./${name}_day.png ${imageDir}/${name}_day.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphing runs once a minute as well from cron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;* * * * * /root/bin/neidetcher_access_log.sh graph
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What that gets you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, lots of stuff there but now we have pretty graphs showing how 
often my site is visited.  As you can see I don&amp;#39;t need to investigate CDN
options just yet.  My &lt;a href=&quot;http://neidetcher.com/metrics.html&quot;&gt;metrics&lt;/a&gt; page shows the
graphs in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/demian0311/fc5b45cc901d36889b5e&quot;&gt;My script&lt;/a&gt; gist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/&quot;&gt;RRDTool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fourmilab.ch/webtools/logtail/&quot;&gt;LogTail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neidetcher.com/metrics.html&quot;&gt;My Metrics Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>April 2014 Lifting</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/04/23/april-2014-lifting.html"/>
   <updated>2014-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/04/23/april-2014-lifting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just a collection of observations related to lifting right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Week 3 now with Finishers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Week 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, week 3 of the 5/3/1 template.  Week 3 is when you lift the most that 
you&amp;#39;re going to lift that month.  The idea is that after week 3 you are going 
to take a rest (deload) for a week.  This seemed like a good time to throw in
finihsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2929/13982370603_20d90153bc_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;depth check&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finishers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishers are ways of doing exercises at the end of a workout that are kind of
un-conventional.  Normal exercises are prescribed with sets and reps and you 
work through them.  Finishers are a-typical.  If you did them all the time you
might burn out but they are good to do occasionally to get results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traits of finishers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you do them at the end of your workout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you do them intensely, nothing is left in the tank at the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;#39;s okay if form goes bad (as long as you&amp;#39;re safe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you do them rarely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are meant to give you a pump (hypertrophy is the goal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of finishers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/hit-on-21s.html&quot;&gt;21s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.muscleandfitness.com/workouts/arms-exercises/explode-your-guns-biceps-blasting-method&quot;&gt;I go, you go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drop_set&quot;&gt;Strip sets, drop sets or running the rack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/andy2.htm&quot;&gt;Super sets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m doing 2 strip sets at the end of every workout for the 3rd week of 5/3/1.  I like 
it.  I don&amp;#39;t have it in my spreadsheet so I could see leaving it out if I&amp;#39;m not feeling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the exercises I&amp;#39;m doing for each day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;press: thin grip bench &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dead: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.exrx.net/WeightExercises/OlympicLifts/RomanianDeadlift.html&quot;&gt;RDL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bench: curls (Sun&amp;#39;s out gun&amp;#39;s out) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squat: front squat &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pull-Up Bar and Symmetry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a pull-up bar.  I got the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.studbarpullup.com/&quot;&gt;Stud Bar&lt;/a&gt;, seemed appropriate
for me.  One of the provided bolts snapped, I may have not drilled deep enough into the rafters.
Even with only 3 bolts in, the thing is solidly in place.  And the bar is thick.  I&amp;#39;m a tubby man
and the bar doesn&amp;#39;t bend at all.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7372/13778097534_6090451413_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;perils&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One bad thing about having pull-up bar is that my 7 year old son climbed up a rope I had hanging 
from it, fell down and broke his arm.  We did have some foam padding under the bar but obviously
it wasn&amp;#39;t enough to prevent that injury.  That entirely sucks and is squarely my fault.  But it&amp;#39;s a 
somewhat safe lesson in his own mortality that will serve him well.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t done pull-ups since I stopped working out at the local gym.  I was doing pull-ups 
in-between every pushing movement as prescribed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jimwendler.com/&quot;&gt;Jim Wendler&lt;/a&gt;.  So yeah
it&amp;#39;s been a year with no pull-ups.  I haven&amp;#39;t tried to see how many I can do.  I&amp;#39;m very conservative
when I introduce or re-introduce movements back into my routine.  So for now I&amp;#39;m just doing 1 
pull-up in-between each pushing movement on press and bench days.  Next month I think I&amp;#39;ll attempt 
2 pull-ups and see where that gets me.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did not expect is that it seems to have helped some lingering shoulder pain I have acquired.
I have been going pretty heavy (relatively for me) with the press.  My PR for the press is 205.
It just enforces the mantra that you should train with symmetry.  I was doing a lot of pushing in 
the vertical plane but no pulling in the vertical plane.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing pull-ups along with backing off the press weight a little bit has my shoulders doing &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;
better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Iso-Lateral&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of backing off on the weight.  I have either stayed level with where my weights were
or in the case of the press I have come down a little bit.  It just seems that I need to not push
it quite as much as I have been.  When you take something away hopefully you&amp;#39;re adding something 
back that moves you forward or challenges you.  I think that&amp;#39;s what I&amp;#39;ve done.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ezinearticles.com/?Isolateral-Exercise---What-is-it-and-Why-is-it-Beneficial?-The-Answer-is-Here!&amp;amp;id=2120443&quot;&gt;Iso-lateral&lt;/a&gt; means that you&amp;#39;re doing something favoring or just using one side of your body.  If 
you&amp;#39;re using a machine you can probably isolate things very well.  If you&amp;#39;re using other equipment
like a kettlebell, dumbell, landmine or pulley you can&amp;#39;t isolate things very well.  But that&amp;#39;s
not so bad because this imbalance causes all sorts of interesting muscles to engage to stabilize
and firm up your body so you can perform the exercise.  Really this is good stuff for the core
and will make for a more solid human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the movements.  I feel like it&amp;#39;s kind of &lt;em&gt;shoring up&lt;/em&gt; my strength.  Building a stronger base.
I was watching a video from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rqy72fYwZdg&amp;amp;t=2m23s&quot;&gt;Mountain Athelete&lt;/a&gt;.  They
train military people and mountaineers.  I believe he used the phrase &lt;em&gt;combat chasis&lt;/em&gt;.  Really
from the chest to the knees, that area that is going to be carrying the load where you really want
to be strong.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the iso-lateral movements I&amp;#39;m doing these days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kettlebell snatch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kettlebell suitcase deadlift&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kettlebell press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;landmine row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kettlebell calf press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kettlebell squat (not a goblet squat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Re-set the Bench&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did the math and figured out how low I could start on the bench, add 5 pounds a month and still
end up at benching 285 at the end of the year.  And that&amp;#39;s where I put my bench.  I still feel 
sub-optimal when I bench.  It&amp;#39;s an exercise that I kind of don&amp;#39;t have a lot of respect for and
I&amp;#39;m in no rush to see it go up.  It&amp;#39;s the typical meat-head barometer for how strong you are but
has little carry-over in the real world.  Unless you find yourself with your back firmly pressed
on a flat surface and a desire to press in a perpendicular direction to your back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nutrition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My paleo-ish  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=permabulker&quot;&gt;perma-bulk&lt;/a&gt; could
probably use some dialing back so here are some tweaks I have been making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;#39;t go looking for food dairy but don&amp;#39;t avoid it, so no snacking on cheese, no more sour cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 scoop of protein and 1 cup of milk post-workout (as opposed to 2 scoops and probably 2 cups)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no half &amp;amp; half in drinks after lunch, my morning coffee will always have half &amp;amp; half I will die on that hill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no snacking except for 3 brazil nuts and 2 90% Lindt squares before bed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no breakfast on days I don&amp;#39;t lift&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low carb 6 days a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moderate carb 1 day a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My music was getting old.  I did the lazy thing and actually &lt;em&gt;bought&lt;/em&gt; some music instead of 
working hard to pirate it.  I should spend 20 minutes to clean up the list below to remove all
the un-necessary information.  It&amp;#39;s especially in-excusable because I&amp;#39;m awesome at VIM.  But 
I&amp;#39;m still not going to do that.  This is what I get when I copy and paste my playlist from
iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got your dubstep, old school rap, pop, new rap, metal.  It&amp;#39;s working for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Is the Shark Attack (Skrillex Remix)     5:21    Shark Attack    Shooting Judas Remixed  Electronic      1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Am Not a Goal-Oriented Person       2:55    Whores  Clean - EP  Rock        4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn Down For What        3:34    DJ Snake &amp;amp; Lil Jon  Turn Down For What - Single Dance       2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breadfan      5:41    Metallica   Garage, Inc.    Rock        1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pompeii       3:34    Bastille    Bad Blood   Alternative     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starships     3:31    Nicki Minaj Starships - Single  Hip-Hop/Rap     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solar Flare Homicide      3:50    Emmure  Speaker Of The Dead WORKOUT     4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Down Low      3:35    AlexAnder and Dr. Ozi       Drumstep        7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel so Close (Radio Edit)        3:26    Calvin Harris   18 Months   Dance       1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recess        3:58    Skrillex    Recess  Dance       3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right Round       3:23    Flo Rida    R.O.O.T.S. (Deluxe Version) Hip-Hop/Rap     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Party Up (Up in Here)     4:29    DMX ...And Then There Was X Hip Hop/Rap     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drinking from the Bottle (feat. Tinie Tempah)     4:00    Calvin Harris   18 Months   Dance       2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Looks        4:07    Whores  Clean - EP  Rock        2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pornstep (feat. The Highbury Whores)      4:38    Dodge &amp;amp; Fuski   Fierce / Pornstep - Single  Dance       2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lost Weekend (feat. Mike Patton)      4:35    The Qemists Join the Q  Electronic      1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periphery - Icarus Lives! - Periphery     3:30            WORKOUT     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do It With a Rockstar     4:25    Amanda Palmer &amp;amp; The Grand Theft Orchestra   Theatre Is Evil Alternative     9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Darkest Nights        3:52    As I Lay Dying  Shadows Are Security    Metalcore       6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bangarang (feat. Sirah)       3:35    Skrillex    Bangarang   Dance       3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bleed     7:23    Meshuggah   ObZen   Rock        6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to Survive        4:40    Chimaira    The Infection   WORKOUT     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android Porn      6:56    Kraddy  Android Porn / Steppin&amp;#39; Razor - Single  Electronic&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cougars, Not Kittens      6:40    Whores  Clean - EP  Rock&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; Down        4:18    Boys Noize  Oi Oi Oi    Electronic      3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vacuity       4:52    Gojira  The Way of All Flesh    Metal       6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuel      4:30    Metallica   Reload  Rock&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the World (Radio Mix)        3:33    Swedish House Mafia Save the World - Single Dance       1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break Those Bones Whose Sinews Gave It Motion     6:57    Meshuggah   Koloss  Metal       2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power Glove       4:21    Knife Party Haunted House - EP  Dance       5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You Can Do It     4:19    Ice Cube    Greatest Hits   Hip Hop/Rap&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rock &amp;#39;n&amp;#39; Roll (Will Take You to the Mountain)     4:44    Skrillex    Scary Monsters and Nice Sprites Dance       8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Your Words     5:24    Lamb Of God Wrath   Metal&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Razor Sharp       4:41    Pegboard Nerds &amp;amp; Tristam    Monstercat 013 - Awakening  Dance       6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feüer Frei       3:13    Rammstein       WORKOUT     2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pound the Alarm       3:26    Nicki Minaj Pink Friday ... Roman Reloaded (Deluxe Edition) Hip-Hop/Rap&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight the Power       4:37    Public Enemy    Power to the People &amp;amp; the Beats - Public Enemy&amp;#39;s Greatest Hits  Hip Hop/Rap&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Up        3:16    50 Cent Get Up - Single Hip-Hop/Rap&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combustion        4:11    Meshuggah   obZen   Metal       2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel So Numb      3:39    Rob Zombie  The Sinister Urge   Hard Rock       5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halo      3:17    Soil    Scars           3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring the Noise       3:46    Public Enemy    It Takes a Nation of Millions to Hold Us Back   Hip Hop/Rap&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straight Outta Compton (2002 Remaster)        4:19    N.W.A.  Straight Outta Compton (2002 Remaster)  Hip Hop/Rap&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Apocalypse     5:01    Metallica   Death Magnetic  Rock        1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reptile&amp;#39;s Theme       3:57    Skrillex    Reptile&amp;#39;s Theme - Single    Dance       9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter Sandman     5:32    Metallica   Metallica   Rock&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can&amp;#39;t Hold Us (feat. Ray Dalton)      4:18    Macklemore &amp;amp; Ryan Lewis The Heist (Deluxe Edition)  Hip Hop/Rap     8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekends!!!       4:45    Skrillex    Weekends!!! (feat. Sirah) - Single  Dance       3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Play And Akka</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2014/04/17/play-and-akka.html"/>
   <updated>2014-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2014/04/17/play-and-akka</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took another lab week to stumble around with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.playframework.com/&quot;&gt;Play Framework&lt;/a&gt;.  I really 
like the way routing works, the controllers 
are nice and simple.  It has all come a long way
and I wish I could use it for my day job.  If I were
doing a green-field web-app with some APIs I&amp;#39;d likely 
reach for Play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to learn a little bit more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reactive_programming&quot;&gt;reactive programming&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;#39;m not bought in enough to go sign the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reactivemanifesto.org/&quot;&gt;reactive manifesto&lt;/a&gt; quite yet.  But a lot of smart people seem to be into it so again I thought I&amp;#39;d look into it.  I put 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/ricochet&quot;&gt;this project up on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Actor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/ricochet/blob/master/app/actors/PersistorActor.scala&quot;&gt;my actor&lt;/a&gt;.  It uses a Scala object singleton to sort of simulate some 
back-end persistence.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;scala language-scala&quot; data-lang=&quot;scala&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;package&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;actors&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;akka.actor.Actor&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;utils._&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;play.api.mvc.Results&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;PersistorActor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Actor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;receive&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEventPost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;duration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dateTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;GaugePersistence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;persist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEventPost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;duration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dateTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEventRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sender&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;GaugePersistence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEventRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Controller/ Actor Client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is my Play Framework controller (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/ricochet/blob/master/app/controllers/ReactiveGauge.scala&quot;&gt;full source&lt;/a&gt;) that creates a pool of actors.
I&amp;#39;m thankful that &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.evilmonkeylabs.com/2013/01/17/Distributing_Akka_Workloads_And_Shutting_Down_After/&quot;&gt;Evil Monkey Labs&lt;/a&gt;
posted some code on how to easily create a pool of Actors.
The Akka documentation wasn&amp;#39;t very straight-forward to me.  I have to admit I didn&amp;#39;t
read it end to end, I was doing more random access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;scala language-scala&quot; data-lang=&quot;scala&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;implicit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;timeout&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Timeout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;system&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ActorSystem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;SimpleSystem&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;persistorActor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;ActorRef&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;system&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;actorOf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Props&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;PersistorActor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;withRouter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;RoundRobinRouter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nrOfInstances&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;simpleRoutedActor&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the actor usage example that you always see.  This is async, fire and
forget.  This goes right on a different thread so the actor can do it&amp;#39;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;scala language-scala&quot; data-lang=&quot;scala&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;persistorActor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEventPost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEvent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;durationOpt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the less than typical way of using actors.  We actually want to get 
a response here.  This uses the implicit timeout from above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;scala language-scala&quot; data-lang=&quot;scala&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;persistorActor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ask&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TimerEventRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;mapTo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;SimpleResult&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More stuff to learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some things that I think I need to learn with respect to Akka and actors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dependency injection with actors &lt;a href=&quot;http://scaldi.org/Scaldi.html&quot;&gt;scaldi&lt;/a&gt; seems to be a good solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating a hierarchy of actors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;configuring actor pools and dispatching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remoting Actors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;handling dead letter situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Squat Fail</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/03/24/squat-fail.html"/>
   <updated>2014-03-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/03/24/squat-fail</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Squat Fail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For squats, it works best when you come up from 
the bottom at least as many times as you go down.
This month, I had some trouble getting out of the
hole.  Luckily I had the camera on me.  I&amp;#39;ve been
getting video more often because I want to keep an
eye on my depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;#39;m getting close to where I want to be
with my lifts I think I have stalled out a bit.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; 
   src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/boezPaZ6DWI&quot; 
   frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been approaching 315 but given my little stumble
here I decided to lower the weights and gradually work
my way back up.  An even 315 will have to wait for 
another few months.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Happened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A buddy that saw the video noticed that my heels 
came up a bit such that I was on the balls of my
feet.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some bad shoulder mobility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bar placement higher than normal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;back angle was too forward for the high bar placement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ended up on the balls of my feet and lost my balance &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides lowering the weight I need to focus on sitting
back into the squat.  Keeping the weight on my heels.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deadlift Goal Achieved</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/02/04/deadlift-goal-achieved.html"/>
   <updated>2014-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/02/04/deadlift-goal-achieved</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Nailed It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago was the first time I tried to attempt 
to deadlift 365 since I failed in November.  It doesn&amp;#39;t 
exactly look like it but the first rep was harder than
the second and third.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of my
lifting goals happen to match up with some convenient 
numbers for adding plates to a bar.  365 is the weight of
a bar, 3 45 pound plates on each side and a 25 pound plate
on each side as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; 
   src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/7nN-Il_HcRw&quot; 
   frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Failed It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is me failing to deadlift 365 back in November.  I thought 
I was close so I tried it for a second time but still failed.
I also failed an attempt at 365 about a year ago.  I&amp;#39;m not even
sure why I tried it.  I think I nailed 315 and then just assumed
I should try to do 365.  I had to scratch and claw for each pound
to get up to 365.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; 
   src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/YyydMg52xg4&quot; 
   frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I think I&amp;#39;ll do for all of my lifts as I reach my 
goal in poundages.  For now I&amp;#39;m just going to think it through
for the deadlift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to keep the weights where they are.  I might even leave the
numbers where they are forever.  From here I see going into 2
phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Increase Reps from 5/3/1 to 7/5/3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge none of this makes sense unless you understand how 5/3/1 works.
Gradually I want to bump up my reps for my 5/3/1 sets.  For example
in February I&amp;#39;m doing 6/4/2.  Like I said I&amp;#39;ll keep the weights where
they are.  Assuming I hit all my lifts, then the following month I&amp;#39;ll 
go to 7/3/5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s how my 5/3/1 sets look for Jan, Feb and Mar look.  I&amp;#39;m leaving 
out deload weeks here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;January&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  5 250   3 267.5 5 287.5
  5 287.5 3 307.5 3 325
  5 325   3 345   1 365
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;February&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  6 250  4 270  6 290
  6 290  4 310  4 325
  6 325  4 345  2 365
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;March&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  7 250  5 270  7 290
  7 290  5 310  5 325
  7 325  5 345  3 365
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the idea is, for the rest of my life I don&amp;#39;t deadlift more than
365 pounds.  I&amp;#39;ll do it once a month and I&amp;#39;ll do it for a triple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Add Cardio with EMOM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I increase my reps of my 5/3/1 sets (now 7/5/3, heh), then I will
introduce some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-intensity_interval_training&quot;&gt;HIIT&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theboxmag.com/crossfit-workouts/emom-every-minute-on-the-minute-a-formula-for-volume-and-skill-development/&quot;&gt;EMOM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For assistance work I always do 3 sets of 10 of whatever exercise I
did for the 5/3/1 sets.  So for deadlifts my first assistance exercise
is deadlifts yet again for 3 sets of 10 reps at 215 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of my deadlift assistance work looks like this:
      bb hip thrust 5 20 185
      kb swing      5 20 53&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll do them as a cycle, so hip thrusts then kettlebell swing then
onto the 2nd round for hip thrusts, more kettlebell swings, you get
the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first month, I guess that&amp;#39;ll be April.  I&amp;#39;ll do the last 2 cycles
as EMOM.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bb hip thrust, kb swing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bb hip thrust, kb swing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bb hip thrust, kb swing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bb hip thrust, kb swing EMOM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bb hip thrust, kb swing EMOM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next month, looking like May I&amp;#39;ll do the last 3 cycles as EMOM and 
on from there until all the sets of my assistance work is EMOM.  This
should really get my heart going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of all this I hope to maintain solid strength and get in 
much better cardio shape.  We&amp;#39;ll see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Java8 Fizz Buzz</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2014/01/17/java8-fizz-buzz.html"/>
   <updated>2014-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2014/01/17/java8-fizz-buzz</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my attempt at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/02/why-cant-programmers-program.html&quot;&gt;FizzBuzz&lt;/a&gt; 
in &lt;a href=&quot;https://jdk8.java.net/download.html&quot;&gt;Java8&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/lambda/&quot;&gt;Lambdas&lt;/a&gt;.  This will 
not go in the Pantheon of awesome code and I&amp;#39;m sure I&amp;#39;ll tweak it as I learn more.  Oh and this is a self-contained 
implementation and unit test, just messing around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not sure if there&amp;#39;s a nicer way to do the predicates inline with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.java.net/jdk8/docs/api/java/util/stream/IntStream.html&quot;&gt;Stream API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish if statements were expressions, that would clean up some of the code. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;d be neato if FizzBuzz was conducive to using function composition to do a divBy15 but it isn&amp;#39;t needed for FizzBuzz. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.java.net/jdk8/docs/api/java/util/stream/IntStream.html#range-int-int-&quot;&gt;Ranges&lt;/a&gt; are nice to see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;java language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;package&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;javafunctional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;java8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;org.junit.Test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;java.util.function.Predicate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;java.util.stream.IntStream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;junit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Assert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;FunctionLiterals&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Predicate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Integer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;divBy3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Predicate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Integer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;divBy5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;testPredicates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;divBy3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;divBy5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;fizzBuzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Integer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;intIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizz&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;divBy3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;intIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Fizz&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;buzz&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;divBy5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;intIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Buzz&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;isEmpty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;buzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;isEmpty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;())?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;intIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;toString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizz&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;buzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;testFizzBuzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Fizz&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizzBuzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Buzz&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizzBuzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;FizzBuzz&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizzBuzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;runit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IntStream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;mapToObj&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ii&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fizzBuzz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ii&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;forEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kids And Lifting</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/01/14/kids-and-lifting.html"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2014/01/14/kids-and-lifting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3690/11787566944_a1715689bf_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Iron&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think lifting weights teaches you a lot.  It can be a metaphor for
many things.  Understanding the concept of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/happiness-in-world/201207/the-power-delaying-gratification&quot;&gt;delayed gratification&lt;/a&gt; 
is is one of the most obvious benefits of training.
Henry Rollins has a great story called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oldtimestrongman.com/strength-articles/iron-henry-rollins&quot;&gt;The Iron&lt;/a&gt;, you should go read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I want my boys to have as many opportunities as possible, I decided 
to start introducing them to weights more seriously with the new year.
They&amp;#39;re aged 6 and 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://startingstrength.com/articles/young_strength_starr.pdf&quot;&gt;Youngsters Need Strength Too&lt;/a&gt;
Bill Starr sites studies that show there is no effect on growth plates or any other overly cautionary
concerns most people have.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advancing in weight is a distant concern.  Here are my goals for them 
in doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be able to lift safely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop the habit of training (it&amp;#39;s something you just do)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;know what hard work is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand good form &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s only one workout and this is it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  exercise                sets  reps  weight
  ----------------------- ----- ----- ------
  press                   3     5     30
  kettlebell deadlift     3     5     26
  bench                   3     5     30
  kettlebell goblet squat 3     5     15
  rope pull 30 feet       3     1     26
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some random points and rationale about the workout:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workout twice a week not on consecutive days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;press&lt;/em&gt; is a vertical push.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;kettlebell deadlift&lt;/em&gt; is vertical pull, covering posterior chain and core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;kettlebell deadlift&lt;/em&gt; demonstrates a neutral spine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;bench&lt;/em&gt; is a horizontal push.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;kettlebell goblet squat&lt;/em&gt; is quads and core. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;rope pull&lt;/em&gt; is a horizontal pull, some posterior chain and core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rope pull is done with a 26 lb kettlebell tied to the end of a 30 foot 
battle rope.  The 3 year old pulls out the empty end of the rope and then 
the 6 year old pulls the weighted end towards him.  Rinse and repeat that
3 times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 6 year old is working on good form and staying safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3 year old does 3 reps of everything instead of 5.  Or instead of 3 reps
he does whatever the heck he wants to have fun.  Usually he&amp;#39;s eager to show
how strong he is and he has a smile on his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2834/11787393173_f55ef43d08_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lifting In 2013</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2013/12/31/lifting-in-2013.html"/>
   <updated>2013-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2013/12/31/lifting-in-2013</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my PRs at the end of the year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press: 200 x 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dead: 360 x 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bench: 245 x 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squat: 300 x 2 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5/3/1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the entire year my programming was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Simplest-Effective-Training-System-Strength-ebook/dp/B00AJ8CIQM/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1388369664&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=5%2F3%2F1&quot;&gt;5/3/1&lt;/a&gt;.  I like the program it affords
a perfect mix of structure and flexibility.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Progress This Year&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following chart doesn&amp;#39;t show what I was maxing out with each month it just
shows what numbers I used to calculate my 5/3/1 workouts.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jimwendler.com/2013/03/the-purpose-of-a-training-max/&quot;&gt;Jim Wendler has a 
write-up on what the training max means&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3817/11634687553_8a54659802_o.png&quot; alt=&quot;531 Training Max by Month&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Beyond 5/3/1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-year I bought &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Beyond-Simple-Training-Extraordinary-Results/dp/1467580309&quot;&gt;Jim Wendler&amp;#39;s new book Beyond 5/3/1&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;#39;m a 
Jim Wendler fan boy so I enjoy reading anything he puts out but I bet most
of the people following 5/3/1 don&amp;#39;t need to read this book.  But whatever, the man
puts out lots of great free information, kick him $10 for the Kindle version wether
or not you use any of the concepts from &lt;em&gt;Beyond 5/3/1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Endurance Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For almost all of my lifts I&amp;#39;m getting close to where I would like my strength 
level to be.  I&amp;#39;ve never done CrossFit but you hear them talk about strength endurance.
That implies that you build a level of strength and then demonstrate endurance over
that strength.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I might start doing is working in some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theboxmag.com/crossfit-workouts/emom-every-minute-on-the-minute-a-formula-for-volume-and-skill-development/&quot;&gt;EMOM&lt;/a&gt; gradually 
in my last sets.  Gradually doing this for all assistance sets.  Keeping all the 
weights the same. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Press&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My press is relatively strong compared to other lifts.  I&amp;#39;m able to make 
continual progress on it.  I don&amp;#39;t feel like I&amp;#39;m over-extending myself, I think
I have more in the tank.  For 2014 it&amp;#39;d be great to inch up to a 225 overhead
press but I could see stalling out before I get there.  205 would be a barbell
with a 45 and a 35 on each side.  Seems respectable for a strict overhead press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part deadlifts went along well.  I continued my conservative progress.
However, I had a failed 365 pound deadlift attempt in November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/YyydMg52xg4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month I did 360 for 1.  When I get up to 360 for 2 I&amp;#39;ll up my weights by
5 pounds.  I might stop increases in deadlift such that I&amp;#39;m doing 365 for set 3 
of my 5/3/1 week.  We&amp;#39;ll see if I get antsy and will want to push for an even
405.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dead, like my squat is not very impressive.  I&amp;#39;m being very conservative with
my back.  I make sure that I can do the reps with perfect form to protect my spine.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bench&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bench is the yellow line up above.  It took a big dip in August.  The root
cause was ego.  I was taking a wide grip on the bench because I was focused on 
the getting numbers up.  Wide grips are used in competition for power lifters
but it&amp;#39;s known that it isn&amp;#39;t the greatest thing for your shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A guy I know gave me a suggestion or at least something to think of.  With 
respect to the bench grip width, in normal life you are almost always using
your pecs with your hands shoulder width apart.  Think of a football lineman
pushing at his opponent, he has his hands shoulder width.  It shouldn&amp;#39;t be a 
huge epiphany I suppose but it helped things click for me.  Oh, and 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jimwendler.com/2012/01/all-about-the-bench-press/&quot;&gt;Jim Wendler&lt;/a&gt; has
said a lot about keeping a narrow grip on the bench for shoulder health as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the wide grip I also noticed that my shoulders were rolling forward
while benching and doing push-ups.  In these movements your pectorals and 
triceps should be doing the majority of the work and your 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dragondoor.com/shoulder_packing_101/&quot;&gt;shoulders should be packed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright that was a lot of words but it really came down to a few things I 
needed to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lower the weight and continue with a conservative progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the last rep, instead of doing as many as possible, just do the prescribed reps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;narrow the grip to shoulder width&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pack the shoulders (or pinch the scapulas) while benching &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m content with my bench being lower.  I&amp;#39;ve been adding 5 pounds a month.
Right now I think that I&amp;#39;ll be content when I am doing a 1RM of 275 on the bench
but again, maybe 315 will be calling once I reach that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Squats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeep I post video of my squat PRs online.  A few years ago I had my &lt;em&gt;squat&lt;/em&gt; up to 
315.  For no reason in particular I decided to get video of my squat form using my
old iPod Nano.  What I saw is some squat form that would make &lt;a href=&quot;http://startingstrength.wikia.com/wiki/Wit_and_Wisdom_of_Mark_Rippetoe&quot;&gt;Mark Rippetoe&lt;/a&gt; cry.  It
was total crap, I was barely doing a 1/4 squat.  Ever since then I have filmed my
heavy squat sets.  I started posting them online to hold myself even more accountable,
that&amp;#39;s the theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A real squat has your femur at least parallel to the floor.  Or easier to judge, the crease of 
your hip should be below the knee.  Here&amp;#39;s one of my last squat attempts for the year.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/CaJIB0vYfk8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My squat is very slowly moving along.  I&amp;#39;m 42 this year I&amp;#39;d like to gradually work
up to a 315 squat and hang there.  I&amp;#39;d like to be someone that can hit a squat triple for 
315 any day of the week.  Among power-lifters that would not be respectable but I&amp;#39;d 
be happy with that for a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where I want to be for 2014&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;#39;m setting the bar low here but this is where I minimally want to
be this year.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press: 205 x 3 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dead: 365 x 3 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bench: 285 x 3 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squat: 315 x 3 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Book Review Functional Programming In Java</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/12/29/book-review-functional-programming-in-java.html"/>
   <updated>2013-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/12/29/book-review-functional-programming-in-java</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Venkat is working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://pragprog.com/book/vsjava8/functional-programming-in-java&quot;&gt;Functional Programming in Java&lt;/a&gt;.  The book is still in Beta right now but it&amp;#39;s 
firming up and I&amp;#39;ve finished it over Christmas
break.  This is a great book.  Venkhat really shows you how the new 
features in Java8 will make your code more awesome and how you can play 
with FP concepts.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this I &lt;a href=&quot;/programming/2013/05/14/book-review-functional-programming-for-java-developers.html&quot;&gt;reviewed FP for Java Developers&lt;/a&gt;.  That was good but it pre-dated the 
finalization of the lambda syntax.  If you can&amp;#39;t switch to Java8 and you
want to do FP then look into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Functional-Programming-Java-Developers-Concurrency/dp/1449311032&quot;&gt;FP for Java Developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venkat&amp;#39;s new book lays out the mechanics of lambda expressions and then goes through how to use
them with the collections APIs and high order functions.  Not much else to say about
the book other than if you&amp;#39;re doing Java8 then this book should be required reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I&amp;#39;m a Simple Man&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7 deals with optimizing recursion.  Chapter 8 is on composing lambda expressions.
Honestly I skimmed those chapters.  After doing the Coursera class on FP in Scala I 
was a recursion monster but at work I still never ended up writing recursive code.
Maybe I&amp;#39;m a knuckle dragger, maybe the problems I solve are work are too simple.
Either way it&amp;#39;s stuff I haven&amp;#39;t had to get good at for my day job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Mini Rant: Of Imperative vs Declarative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;#39;m being a bit of a jack-ass here but I don&amp;#39;t get the distinction.  Sure, 
it&amp;#39;s telling the computer &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do something as opposed to &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you want it
to do.  But I see this as more of a difference in degree and not as much a difference
in kind.  It just seems like what we are calling declarative programming is just 
further up the API design continuum away from bad and cumbersome APIs.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in Java8 we say that the collection APIs and the ability to use lambdas
creates more declarative code.  I just kind of see it as having more awesome APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Book Review Phoenix Project</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/12/04/book-review-phoenix-project.html"/>
   <updated>2013-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/12/04/book-review-phoenix-project</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This book is about an IT manager.  I don&amp;#39;t want to give spoilers because
even though the book isn&amp;#39;t perfect I think that anyone in the software
business should read it.  To that end I don&amp;#39;t want to ruin the book for 
you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many of the situations that came up in the book I was reminded of
very similar things that have happened to me in my career.  The situations
were similar in the technical nature of what happened.  They all seemed
very plausible and relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also things that happened that were driven by the business that
felt familiar.  Companies and IT departments often find themselves doing
sub-optimal things for very compelling reasons.  Again, these types of
situations were very relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is well crafted to translate the lean practices from manufacturing
into software.  It all lines up a little bit too nice but it is quite
instructional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you get it, the likelyhood that you will end up in an organization
that is receptive to some good lean and devops practices is remote.  It&amp;#39;s
even more remote that you will find yourself in the right position in such
a company. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you won&amp;#39;t be able to change your IT organization the week after you
read this book I still think you should read this book.  You should get as
many of your co-workers to read this book as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Getting Around Groovy Linkage Error</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/10/17/getting-around-groovy-linkage-error.html"/>
   <updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/10/17/getting-around-groovy-linkage-error</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;A Hystrix Grails Plugin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying my hand at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/hystrix-circuit-breaker&quot;&gt;creating a Grails plugin&lt;/a&gt;
that will pull in the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/Hystrix&quot;&gt;Netflix Hystrix circuit breaker&lt;/a&gt; 
capability in your &lt;a href=&quot;http://grails.org/&quot;&gt;Grails&lt;/a&gt; application.
I have never written Grails plugins before.  Holy cow writing Grails 
plugins is surprisingly straightforward.  It&amp;#39;s awesome. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason I&amp;#39;m doing this is because we finally stumbled onto
the fact that using Grails plugins to manage your common code in an
enterprise is a good idea.  So we&amp;#39;re doing that at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m doing this with Netflix Hystrix because we use circuit breakers
at work in our Scala services.  Also, I am working on a talk to give in 2014 about
how to harden your application with respect to outgoing calls and the
concerns you should have with that.  Yes, I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circuit_breaker_design_pattern&quot;&gt;circuit breakers&lt;/a&gt;
are one of those concerns you should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating the Hystrix into a Grails plugin has been fun and surprisingly easy.
The hooks that Grails gives you for hacking at the web.xml file are nice.  My 
problems began when I wanted to configure my newly created circuit breaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groovy has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jira.codehaus.org/browse/GROOVY-6286&quot;&gt;known problem (Cannot call Java static method with same name as inner class (LinkageError))&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;#39;s amusing that the author of that issue was attempting to do the
same thing I am; configure the Netflix Hystrix API.  I&amp;#39;m not sure how common 
it is to have a static method with the same name as an inner class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offending class is &lt;a href=&quot;http://netflix.github.io/Hystrix/javadoc/com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties.html&quot;&gt;HystrixCommandProperties&lt;/a&gt;.
If you search that page for &lt;em&gt;Setter&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;#39;ll see the inner class and 
the static factory method they want you to use to create a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  LinkageError occurred when processing request: [GET] /hystrix-circuit-breaker/test
  loader constraint violation: when resolving method &amp;quot;com.netflix.hystrix.HystrixCommandProperties.Setter()Lcom/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties$Setter;&amp;quot; the class loader (instance of org/codehaus/groovy/runtime/callsite/CallSiteClassLoader) of the current class, com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties$Setter, and the class loader (instance of groovy/lang/GroovyClassLoader) for resolved class, com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties, have different Class objects for the type com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties$Setter used in the signature. Stacktrace follows:
  org.codehaus.groovy.grails.web.servlet.mvc.exceptions.ControllerExecutionException: Executing action [index] of controller [hystrix.circuit.breaker.TestController] in plugin [hystrix-circuit-breaker] caused exception: Runtime error executing action
     at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor$Worker.runTask(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:895)
     at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor$Worker.run(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:918)
     at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:680)
  Caused by: org.codehaus.groovy.grails.web.servlet.mvc.exceptions.ControllerExecutionException: Runtime error executing action
    ... 3 more
  Caused by: java.lang.reflect.InvocationTargetException
    ... 3 more
  Caused by: java.lang.LinkageError: loader constraint violation: when resolving method &amp;quot;com.netflix.hystrix.HystrixCommandProperties.Setter()Lcom/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties$Setter;&amp;quot; the class loader (instance of org/codehaus/groovy/runtime/callsite/CallSiteClassLoader) of the current class, com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties$Setter, and the class loader (instance of groovy/lang/GroovyClassLoader) for resolved class, com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties, have different Class objects for the type com/netflix/hystrix/HystrixCommandProperties$Setter used in the signature
    at hystrix.circuit.breaker.DodgyStringReverser.createSetter(TestController.groovy:31)
    at hystrix.circuit.breaker.DodgyStringReverser.&amp;lt;init&amp;gt;(TestController.groovy:36)
    at hystrix.circuit.breaker.TestController.index(TestController.groovy:18)
    ... 3 more
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groovy is the king of wild-ass options to call stuff so I thought 
I would try a bunch of different possibilities to see if they get me
around this issue.  I won&amp;#39;t show all the ways that didn&amp;#39;t work. 
Here&amp;#39;s the way that seems to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  static HystrixCommandProperties.Setter createHystrixCommandPropertiesSetter(){
      HystrixCommandProperties.invokeMethod(&amp;quot;Setter&amp;quot;, null)
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/hystrix-circuit-breaker/blob/master/grails-app/controllers/hystrix/circuit/breaker/TestController.groovy&quot;&gt;here&amp;#39;s a link to my silly example that proves the concept&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Beginning Cryptography With Java</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/09/27/beginning-cryptography-with-java.html"/>
   <updated>2013-09-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/09/27/beginning-cryptography-with-java</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Getting my Ass Handed to Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work our PCI compliant Grails application needs to make 2-way SSL calls to
another PCI compliant SOAP service.  Well you know this is gonna kind of suck
for a little bit, you have to assume it&amp;#39;ll take a few days to get everything
set up right.  It turned out that it took me a few weeks to get all this done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some legit distractions in that time but it took me much longer than it
should have.  What hurts even more is that the main issue I had was nothing to
do with SSL.  However, the lack of knowledge and confidence in SSL kind of 
prevented me from seeing my problems clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRISM_(surveillance_program&quot;&gt;NSA/ PRISM&lt;/a&gt;)
scandal has me a bit more interested in privacy and security.  Digging into
the security APIs and the pieces involved gave me a greater appreciation for
current events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let&amp;#39;s Learn Me Some Security&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I resolved to learn more about security and SSL as it applies to the JVM 
platform.  Honestly I initially thought I would take the Coursera class
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/crypto&quot;&gt;Cryptography I&lt;/a&gt;.  But the math 
notation scared me and I was concerned that after investing 6 weeks of my
time I still wouldn&amp;#39;t know the Java APIs very well or have a solid 
practical understanding.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to just crack a book on my own and learn some Java security.  It&amp;#39;s
a weird space in that there hasn&amp;#39;t been a lot of advancement in the APIs.  I 
guess that means that they created the initial APIs for Java well enough
such that there isn&amp;#39;t any serious churn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That lead me to a 2005 dead-tree book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Beginning-Cryptography-with-Java.productCd-0764596330.html&quot;&gt;Beginning Cryptography with Java&lt;/a&gt;.
As far as I know you can&amp;#39;t even get it in an electronic version but that was
alright because I had some trips ahead of me and it was something I could read
to keep my mind off of the impending doom from airplane take-offs and landings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Affirmation that Scala is Cool&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is in Java, 2005.  At my day job I do Scala and Groovy.  I decided to
do the examples.  The process of implementing the Java examples in Scala was
surprisingly fun and re-affirmed how flippin awesome Scala is.  Code shrunk
and became more expressive, got to the core of what we were doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to look at a few of the examples I did they&amp;#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/security&quot;&gt;up on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Amor Fati</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/life/2013/08/12/amor-fati.html"/>
   <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/life/2013/08/12/amor-fati</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just here for posterity.&lt;br&gt;
Awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://grooveshark.com/#!/s/Amor+Fati/52Zo9a?src=5&quot;&gt;song&lt;/a&gt;, lyrics and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amor_fati&quot;&gt;concept&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
Don&#39;t try to find
Words now, you fall
Then go, reach out
The choice is yours to find

This life you&#39;ve got
The light to guide
Your faith decides
The roads you&#39;re going to find

Realize
So tired
Got hope, desire
Even though it&#39;s hard to forget
What you can&#39;t afford now
Chasing all your thoughts, you know that
You&#39;ll be all right in time

This life you&#39;ve got
The light to guide
Your faith decides
The roads you&#39;re going to find

This life you&#39;ve got
The light to guide
Your faith decides
The roads you&#39;re going to find
&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Intellij Is Good</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/07/12/intellij-is-good.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/07/12/intellij-is-good</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This seems to be a theme lately where I&amp;#39;m late to the party, taking a long time
to &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; something that is common knowledge to most folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Groovy / Grails Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was beating my head against the wall using &lt;a href=&quot;http://grails.org/products/ggts&quot;&gt;GGTS&lt;/a&gt;.
For example it was astonishing to me that GGTS didn&amp;#39;t understand that I should have a 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://grails.org/doc/2.2.1/ref/Servlet%20API/request.html&quot;&gt;request&lt;/a&gt; available to me 
while working with Controllers.  No code completion, I was all on my own.  GGTS 
couldn&amp;#39;t help me out at all.  Man I hope it&amp;#39;s a PEBKAC problem but I couldn&amp;#39;t get it working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I bit the bullet and started evaluating the newest version of IntelliJ.  After meeting
some resistance[^1] at work to justify the expense 
I decided to pay for a license out
of my own pocket.  That&amp;#39;s how good I think it has been for my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Scala and PlayFramework Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I have done in my day job is use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scala-ide.org/&quot;&gt;TypeSafe Scala IDE&lt;/a&gt; 
for my Scala programming.  Really that wasn&amp;#39;t going too bad at all.  TypeSafe is 
dog-fooding it and they&amp;#39;re doing a pretty good job.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ also has great support for Scala and the PlayFramework.  After hours I&amp;#39;m playing
with Play, no complaints there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t fully pulled in our large Scala code-base at work quite yet.  We&amp;#39;ll see how that
goes, not expecting much trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Productivity Boosters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big things to re-map &amp;#8984;-R to re-run my last tests.  I do that in
Eclipse and it works out really good.  I&amp;#39;m a very proficient with the keyboard but
day to day the function keys are dead to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big thing that has been helpful is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/164&quot;&gt;IdeaVim&lt;/a&gt;
plugin.  It&amp;#39;s 95% perfect for me.  I&amp;#39;m real quick to get around using it.  The last
5% that doesn&amp;#39;t work the way I want is really just indenting and outdenting a block
of text.  It doesn&amp;#39;t work the same way VIM does.  It&amp;#39;s great to be able to keep my
brain in VIM mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1]: It&amp;#39;s not quite as bad as it sounds, they paid for an older version of IntelliJ for me
previously but I wanted them to pay for the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Book Review Functional Programming For Java Developers</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/05/14/book-review-functional-programming-for-java-developers.html"/>
   <updated>2013-05-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/05/14/book-review-functional-programming-for-java-developers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First off, this is a small book.  72 pages including a glossary.  I was able to read
it on a plne ride from Louisiana to Denver.  Like the tagline says, I hope I never
need this book.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the title suggests, the book is about making Java more functional.  On my team 
we spend half our time in Groovy and half on Scala.  I suppose we 
have done similar things in Groovy.   The support that Groovy has for 
closures makes it easier than it would have been in Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also covers what is coming in Java for more FP features like closures.  The 
syntax looks clunky but I could see living with it if I had no choice.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the book useful in reviewing and appreciating where I&amp;#39;m at.  How things 
were in Java and how nice things are in Scala.  Even if you don&amp;#39;t need to do 
functional programming in Java right now I think this book is a good read.
If my current gig fell apart and I had to do Java fulltime then I would
grab this book to keep my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>April 2013 Month In Review</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2013/04/27/april-2013-month-in-review.html"/>
   <updated>2013-04-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2013/04/27/april-2013-month-in-review</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Home Gym&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with some bro leisurely doing super-sets that
included chain curls in the only available squat rack that uses standard weights (non metric).
It was my squat day, oh man.  I lifted at Red&amp;#39;s for a year and it&amp;#39;s alright, but their equipment setup 
is goofy.  No wonder they have so many machines as opposed to barbells and plates; no one puts anything
away at Red&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started to put together a home gym.  I have a horrible barbell that I got for free.  I have a set
of hi-temp bumper plates (recycled tires) from Rogue and a bench and squat stand from Valor.  I got some
small standard weights for Ryder&amp;#39;s birthday this year.  Those are good for shoulder dumbell work.  Also
I had a few kettlebellls.  I&amp;#39;m able to get in everything I need with this equipment, it&amp;#39;s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workouts are going great.  The weather in Louisiana is awesome this time of year we&amp;#39;ll see how it is 
when it gets very hot this summer and when it gets chilly in the following winter.
What&amp;#39;s especially cool is on week 4 of 5/3/1 where you&amp;#39;re de-loading.  I don&amp;#39;t have to drive 15 minutes
each way to the gym just to kind of go through the motions and not push myself too hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/neidetcher/8655404670/&quot; title=&quot;Home gym by neidetcher, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8256/8655404670_4289e7d99a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Home gym&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Too Aggressive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 5/3/1 you&amp;#39;re supposed to up your upper body lifts by 5 lbs and lower
body lifts by 10 lbs every month.  For April I decided to up my deadlift
by 15 lbs and my press by 10 lbs.  For those exercises I was hitting 10 
reps for week 3 of 5/3/1 regularly and I thought I should bump it up 
more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;April numbers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pres: 170x6 (197 C1RM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deadlift: 330x3 (349 C1RM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bench: 270x5 (304 C1RM) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squat: 270x3 (286 C1RM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Squat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still get video of my squat and put it online, especially on the 5/3/1 week.  I really want to keep myself honest here.  This shot is kind of low, off of my
bench but I can see my thigh make a brief appearance above my hip crease so I think I&amp;#39;m in good shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/jmFrvlQz5Ik&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>In Praise Of The Full Time Employee</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/03/17/in-praise-of-the-full-time-employee.html"/>
   <updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/03/17/in-praise-of-the-full-time-employee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As software engineeers we have to turn our attention to thought leaders.
These might be consultants, blog authors, book authors, speakers, software authors.
Usually they have short engagements with companies.  Their skills run deep into 
their chosen technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#39;s right for us to look up to these guys and to use them as resources.  But I also think we tend to overlook the FTE of the software world.  Their 
careers might not be as sexy, they might not work with the latest technologies 
but they deserve some recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the outset here I gotta say this is self serving.  I&amp;#39;m a working stiff
FTE.  I&amp;#39;ve thought about contracting a few times in my career but I always found
a reason to chicken out.  So this is in no way a condemnation of consultants that
specialize in specific technology for short term engagements.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s more, I consider many of those very guys friends, occasional drinking
buddies and dare I say mentors.  Scott Davis, Tim Berglund, Matthew McCullough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Intellectual Property&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When companies talk about their intellectual property they probably don&amp;#39;t think
of their software engineers.  I think this is a mistake.  In many aspects of the
business no one knows how things get done like software engineers.  No one knows
the algorithms, where the data comes from and who the data goes to like the
software engineers.  If you run a business, your software engineers that are 
full time employees are your intellectual property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fixing the Disfunction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full time employees know that just as they are going to have to live in a code
base they are also going to have to live in an organizational chart.  They care
more about hiring the right team members.  They care about pulling other team 
members up.  They also care about establishing long-term relationships within
the organization that benefit the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sleeping in Your Own House&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve had a career of living with your own software, design, architecture and
coding decisions then you go about these decisions differently.  By &amp;#39;living with&amp;#39;
I mean that you are present for the inception of a project, the initial development
and you are around to support the software for a few years.  If you&amp;#39;ve done that
a few times in your career I think you get an appreciation for the impact of
decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate to take the steam out of my argument but I have to say that in each one 
of these areas I&amp;#39;ve seen short-term contractors have a positive effect. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Smoke Tests For Your System</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/02/24/smoke-tests-for-your-system.html"/>
   <updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/02/24/smoke-tests-for-your-system</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Me and another team member took our most recent lab week to do something incredibly un-sexy.  Our resumes have no new libraries, buzz-words or languages that we can add.  We decided to use some old-school tools to create a very tactical set of smoke tests for our system and for the back-end systems that we depend on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/neidetcher/8546486548/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8378/8546486548_66de3d31dc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smoke_test_console&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our system is used by many clients.  When we get requests we then turn around and talk to about 20 different back-end systems.  Many times we are caught in the middle when there are anomalies found by our clients.  When this happens we have to turn to the logs to see if there&amp;#39;s a problem with a system we depend on.  We also didn&amp;#39;t have much visibility when our systems were not acting as they should. The principle is this.  Create a shell script that will run a bunch of other shell scripts in a directory.  If the script sends back an exit status that is bad (other than 1) we will consider that test failed.  The runner has a simple check for that and will echo PASS/ FAIL based on what we get back.  We also color the text green or red based on the results.  3/4 of my career has been about making red things green. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/neidetcher/8546486586/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8531/8546486586_752877ecc9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;smoke_test_html&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output is so simple that my wife looked at a screen with a bunch of red and said, &amp;quot;that doesn&amp;#39;t look good.&amp;quot;  I&amp;#39;m not sure if we&amp;#39;ll opensource it, there isn&amp;#39;t much intellectual property to speak of.  We decided to set up the scripts to run in a cron job once an hour and generate an HTML report showing the same type of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set a low bar on the smoke tests, sometimes they use cURL to POST a SOAP request and we just look at the response to see a specific piece of information is present.  Sometimes we just use NMAP to convince us that the port is warm on the far end and NMAP at least thinks it&amp;#39;s the right type of application.  The idea is that these tests should be written in 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re not sure how these will be used.  We hope that folks that support operations (including developers) will see new problems that come up not only as an opportunity to diagnose the matter at hand but to also add another smoke test that will give us a more clear indication of the problem the next time around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an incredibly tactical bit of software that won&amp;#39;t win us any design awards but it has already paid off a handful of times.  I regret that we didn&amp;#39;t put something together like this sooner.  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Maven3 Maven2 Mixup On Mac</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/01/05/maven3-maven2-mixup-on-mac.html"/>
   <updated>2013-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2013/01/05/maven3-maven2-mixup-on-mac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At first my Mac was all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  ~/opt/maven/bin&amp;gt;mvn --version  
  Exception in thread &amp;quot;main&amp;quot; java.lang.NoClassDefFoundError: org/codehaus/plexus/classworlds/launcher/Launcher  
  Caused by: java.lang.ClassNotFoundException: org.codehaus.plexus.classworlds.launcher.Launcher  
  at java.net.URLClassLoader$1.run(URLClassLoader.java:202)  
  at java.security.AccessController.doPrivileged(Native Method)  
  at java.net.URLClassLoader.findClass(URLClassLoader.java:190)  
  at java.lang.ClassLoader.loadClass(ClassLoader.java:306)  
  at sun.misc.Launcher$AppClassLoader.loadClass(Launcher.java:301)  
  at java.lang.ClassLoader.loadClass(ClassLoader.java:247)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I&amp;#39;m like (in my ~/.bashrc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  export M3_HOME=$OPT/maven  
  export M2\_HOME=$M3\_HOME  
  export PATH=$M3_HOME/bin:$PATH
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now it&amp;#39;s all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;  ~/opt/maven/bin&amp;gt;./mvn --version  
  Apache Maven 3.0.4 (r1232337; 2012-01-17 02:44:56-0600)  
  Maven home: /Users/demian/opt/maven  
  Java version: 1.6.0_37, vendor: Apple Inc.  
  Java home: /System/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/1.6.0.jdk/Contents/Home  
  Default locale: en_US, platform encoding: MacRoman  
  OS name: &amp;quot;mac os x&amp;quot;, version: &amp;quot;10.8.2&amp;quot;, arch: &amp;quot;x86_64&amp;quot;, family: &amp;quot;mac&amp;quot;  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Java Jdk 1.7 On Mac 1.8.2</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/12/14/java-JDK-1.7-on-mac-1.8.2.html"/>
   <updated>2012-12-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/12/14/java-JDK-1.7-on-mac-1.8.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been doing Scala and Groovy at the day job for about a year now.  For some side work I thought I&amp;#39;http://neidetcher.blogspot.comd use Java, there obviously aren&amp;#39;http://neidetcher.blogspot.comt enough semi-colons in my life.  I haven&amp;#39;http://neidetcher.blogspot.comt touched 1.7 yet and setting it up on my Mac wasn&amp;#39;http://neidetcher.blogspot.comt incredibly intuitive.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to do more poking around to arrive at this than I wish I had to.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding the actual download from Oracle is easy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installing Java 1.7 from Oracle I added this to my ~/.bashrc to actually use it.  Not sure if the install should&amp;#39;http://neidetcher.blogspot.comve done this or if I missed some steps I was supposed to take.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;export JRE_HOME=/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.7.0_10.jdk/Contents/Home/&lt;br&gt;
  export JAVA_HOME=$JRE_HOME&lt;br&gt;
  export JDK_HOME=$JRE_HOME&lt;br&gt;
  export PATH=$JAVA_HOME/bin:$PATH  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And holy cow Oracle does not make it easy to find out how to download the JDK 1.7 API documentation.  Got to have it local for coding on an airplane.  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Another Look At Play2</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/11/19/another-look-at-play2.html"/>
   <updated>2012-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/11/19/another-look-at-play2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Neidetcher: Another Look at Play2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.playframework.org/assets/images/logos/normal.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.playframework.org/assets/images/logos/normal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://raibledesigns.com/rd/search?q=play&quot;&gt;Matt Raible has some good writeups on Play2&lt;/a&gt;.  We switched to Scala about a year ago.  For lab week, a few of us evaluated Play earlier this year.  At the time I mostly worked with the persistence layer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/playframework/Play20/wiki/ScalaAnorm&quot;&gt;anorm&lt;/a&gt;.  Our conclusion was that it wasn&amp;#39;t quite ready for what we wanted to do. 
Just recently I finished a lab week and decided to take another look at Play.  Here are some conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The big question is, compared to what.  At work we use Grails on the web side and Scala on the back-end.  The reality is that we leverage front-end engineers to help us make Time Warner Cable web sites look and behave well.  In our situation I don&amp;#39;t think I can recommend it.  But if you&amp;#39;re in a hardcore Scala shop and your Scala engineers can do enough of the front-end work then Play might be a good option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with routes and templates felt a lot like Android development.  You work in a non-code DSL to create your routes and that turns into code that you write against.  Same for templates, they just turn into functions.  sbt run fires up their own netty server, it&amp;#39;s solid.  It does a great job picking up changes. I didn&amp;#39;t restart the play development server for a few days and it didn&amp;#39;t miss anything.  Play also gives you helpful error messages in the browser when there are problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Routes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
They&amp;#39;re handled in a text file.  I guess it&amp;#39;s good because there&amp;#39;s no cruft surrounding the definition of your routes.  It&amp;#39;s bad because I think Scala is the perfect language for defining an internal DSL to handle routes.  It&amp;#39;d be great to have IDE support while working with routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controllers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Everything feels very idiomatic to Scala.  For example optional parameters are (drum-roll) Options.  Play doesn&amp;#39;t have you use servlet filters, you just wrap functions.  The controllers themselves are not easy to test but there are workarounds such that you can do good unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Templating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;#39;s familiar to someone used to Scala.  Templates are just functions and have input parameters with types.  This gets statically checked and your IDE will bark at you if you send the wrong data type into a template.  I think that&amp;#39;s awesome.  The templating is not as rich as Groovy Server Pages.  For the actual templating work there is no good IDE support.  It&amp;#39;d be great if TypeSafe took this on.  The templating that Play gives you would be painful for front-end engineers that are only familiar with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
They have utilities to help with testing.  All the examples use Specs, I haven&amp;#39;t got the Specs memo yet, still using jUnit (get off my porch).  The biggest problem is that the controllers are objects so it&amp;#39;s hard to do good unit testing.  I found a workaround that someone suggested.  Basically your controller is a class, in this case taking a dependency via the constructor.  Then the object that you tell Play about in the routes extends that class.  This seems to work in my toy example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;object MockUp extends controllers.MockUp(new ProductionGuidCryptoServiceProvider()) {}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Setup</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/efficiency/2012/11/16/the-setup.html"/>
   <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/efficiency/2012/11/16/the-setup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Neidetcher: The Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite blogs is &lt;a href=&quot;http://usesthis.com/&quot;&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt;.  They feature various people that use computers in one way or another to do their job and simply ask them what their setup is.  Well since they haven&amp;#39;t asked me what my setup is yet (not realizing that I&amp;#39;m kind of a big deal) I&amp;#39;m going to just post this on my own.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Who are you, and what do you do? I&amp;#39;m a software engineer.  I have worked mostly for telecommunications companies.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most challenging job I had was leading up a small but capable development team responsible for routing phone calls, including geo-spatial 911 traffic.  This was at a startup without much support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#39;m a Senior Engineer at Time Warner Cable.  My home office is in Denver, Colorado but I work remote in Lafayette, Louisiana.  I fly back about once a month.  The team I&amp;#39;m on works on the services that IP devices use to get streaming television content.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What hardware do you use? My main computer is a MacBookPro 15&amp;quot; from 2010.  I also have a MacPro Desktop.  Each computer has a 27&amp;quot; Thunderbolt Display.  I was skeptical at first but the Apple Magic Mouse is an amazing piece of equipment.  I use 1 standard keyboard for the desktop but primarily I use the bluetooth keyboard.  I wouldn&amp;#39;t mind having the bigger size but the travel from home keys to the mouse seems like an eternity compared to the bluetooth keyboard.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have an iPad 2 for work.  I use it to validate software releases, cable channel updates.  I also have an Asus Transformer to do the same thing on the Android platform.  I don&amp;#39;t write the client code but the team I&amp;#39;m on is responsible for many of the back end services that these devices talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My phone is an LG P999 Android phone.  Works great, has all the apps I need; Evernote, Pandora, Dropbox, Google Reader.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;And what software? I run MacOS on both machines.  The laptop is 10.6, the desktop is 10.7.  I hear so much griping about upgrading the OS that I don&amp;#39;t mind waiting a while until the kinks get worked out.  Before going to the Mac a few years ago I was strictly a Linux user.  It has been a smooth transition to the Mac.  I still feel comfortable whenever I go back to Linux.  If Apple gets too stupid I&amp;#39;ll probably switch back.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time in the IDE.  I run &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eclipse.org/&quot;&gt;Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scala-ide.org/&quot;&gt;Scala-IDE&lt;/a&gt; plugin.  I also use a code coverage plugin for Eclipse that can handle Scala called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jmhofer/eCobertura&quot;&gt;eCobertura&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having an IDE I spend a lot of my time in the console, for that I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://iterm.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;iTerm&lt;/a&gt;.  Being a long-time VIM user I&amp;#39;m thankful for &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/macvim/&quot;&gt;MacVim&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#39;s a great distribution of VIM.  I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; for installing commandline tools that are missing from the Mac.  At work and in my personal development we use &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; exclusively.  On my desktop I run &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenkins-ci.org/&quot;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt; for continuous integration.  It polls the git repository on my laptop and our remote GitHub Enterprise servers at work.  It continuously compiles our code, runs tests and generates reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using a browser for development I will typically use Chrome.  The Chrome plugins I use are for either maintaining privacy or doing software development.  I use Poster, Edit this Cookie, AdBlock, Chrome Nanny, Ghostery, Time Tracker, Evernote and &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/https-everywhere/gcbommkclmclpchllfjekcdonpmejbdp&quot;&gt;HTTPS Everywhere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.share-mouse.com/&quot;&gt;ShareMouse&lt;/a&gt; to make both computers and monitors feel like one big computer.  The price is right (free in my case) but it&amp;#39;s occasionally glitchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For remote work these come in handy: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/time-zones/id448041594?mt=12&quot;&gt;TimeZone&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://beta.skype.com/en/&quot;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.me/&quot;&gt;join.me&lt;/a&gt; for impromptu screen sharing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of information, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;DropBox&lt;/a&gt; to sync files, Pomodoro on occasion to focus, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stereopsis.com/flux/&quot;&gt;f.lux&lt;/a&gt; to save my eyes when working after dark, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; as an app launcher and searcher, &lt;a href=&quot;http://markedapp.com/&quot;&gt;Marked&lt;/a&gt; for previewing MarkDown files. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mindnode.com/&quot;&gt;MindNode&lt;/a&gt; to create mind maps, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pandabarapp.com/&quot;&gt;PandaBar&lt;/a&gt; to make listening to Pandora radio not depend on Adobe Air (WTF) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fikovnik/ShiftIt&quot;&gt;ShiftIt&lt;/a&gt; to easily organize windows.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What would be your dream setup? Pretty much my same setup but with more RAM.  Maybe some SSDs.  The Scala compiler does a lot of work for you so you need top end hardware when you&amp;#39;re doing any Scala project that is beyond trivial.  Although our own informal analysis at work seems to indicate that SSDs don&amp;#39;t buy you too much for building Scala code, seems that good old fashioned RAM and processor speed is what you need..&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that I&amp;#39;d like to have a screaming ThinkPad or AlienWare laptop running some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; Linux variant.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Functional Programming Principles In Scala</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/11/09/functional-programming-principles-in-scala.html"/>
   <updated>2012-11-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/11/09/functional-programming-principles-in-scala</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Functional Programming Principles in Scala&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;#39;s the deal, I was dreading the thought of doing another assignment in the Odersky Scala course on Coursera.  I have other projects I want to move on to and man I&amp;#39;m not built for the academic side.  Then they send out an email telling everyone the minimum number of points we need to complete the course.  Alt-tab over to a Google Doc spreadsheet, do some quick math and presto, I have way more than enough points.  So, I punted on the last assignment.  Yep, I&amp;#39;m that guy, I wrapped up my CS degree with a D in post-calc stats to get the diploma.  That&amp;#39;ll work.
Besides my weak finish the course was awesome.  If you&amp;#39;re in the Scala space and you are anything short of a wizard I don&amp;#39;t understand why you wouldn&amp;#39;t jump on the opportunity to get instruction from Martin Odersky himself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The Course The focus of the course, as you would imagine, is functional programming.  They take much inspiration from&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/&quot;&gt;SICP&lt;/a&gt;.  I don&amp;#39;t know how much of it was SICP or Martin Odersky himself but the course laid out the proper motivation and revelation of information such that my brain was willing and able to accept it.  This was a well thought out, professional course. 
50,000 people signed up for the course.  I don&amp;#39;t know how many people finished it.  The course developers created an automated system that analyzed your code to make sure it passed their own tests along with some other code analysis.  For example I had some code implemented that passed tests but it didn&amp;#39;t use the &lt;em&gt;groupBy&lt;/em&gt; capability in collections.  That was the point of the exercise so they dinged me.  Fair enough, they&amp;#39;re checking lots of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the automated nature, the programming assignments have to structured in a particular way.  They have to lead you down a path.  They can&amp;#39;t just give you an assignment and a blank canvas.  I think this is okay.  But it&amp;#39;s a different approach to programming assignments and worth recognizing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;To Those That Come After Here are some things I recommend to someone taking the course when it is offered next.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Get the SICP book and refer to it, it helped a few times.  Odersky mentions it and I think it&amp;#39;s fair game to refer to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  I didn&amp;#39;t do any of the video quizes, I don&amp;#39;t think it hurt me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Leverage the Scala-IDE worksheet, dump code in there and play, I think it&amp;#39;s better than the REPL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  The forums were sometimes (not very often) helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Submit early and often.  You get great feedback.  Some co-workers found that if you put print statements in your code you&amp;#39;ll see the output in the online feedback, this can give you some indications of the additional test scenarios they are using to evaluate your code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The Cheating 9 co-workers and myself have our own Skype room dedicated to the course.  No one wanted to cheat, we all wanted to get a lot out of the class.  We even made sure that no one gave away&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;spoilers&lt;/em&gt; before the projects were due.  But we also knew that we would benefit greatly by looking at each others work when we were done with assignments.  I actually learned some cool stuff and it was a great time for me to accept the information since I just got done spending hours trying to solve the same problem.  So I was one of the guys that had his assignments up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. 
Then we get the email from the admins that we need to take it down.  That&amp;#39;s all cool but they cited how we signed an agreement acknowledging we wouldn&amp;#39;t post our stuff or whatever.  I wish you could see my face but let&amp;#39;s just say, &lt;strong&gt;no one fuckin reads EULAs&lt;/strong&gt;.  If you don&amp;#39;t already know that, especially if you&amp;#39;re in software I&amp;#39;m not sure what to say.  So I took it down from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and put it on a private repo on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/&quot;&gt;bitbucket&lt;/a&gt;.  If you don&amp;#39;t already know, you get free private git repos from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/&quot;&gt;bitbucket&lt;/a&gt;, good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;On From Here I&amp;#39;m doing things out of order here but I&amp;#39;m going to go through the Scala Koans from here.  Just to loop back and go thru the basics some more.  In the forums the course administrators say they plan on offering additional Scala classes through Coursera.  I look forward to seeing what they offer.&lt;/h4&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stairway To Scala</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/2012/10/31/stairway-to-scala.html"/>
   <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/2012/10/31/stairway-to-scala</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The team I am on at Time Warn Cable has been doing Scala for almost a year now.  5 of us flew out to San Francisco to attend Stairway to Scala training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training was great, I really enjoyed the style of having 2 instructors.  One of them doing traditional lessons and the other one would work on the REPL.  To engineers things are more real when you can see running code.  It&amp;#39;s obvious that Dick and Bill put lots of effort into the curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend the training.  Dick Wall and Bill Venners are awesome instructors.  The Time Warner Cable crew was pretty punchy and the instructors managed to keep their cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Spare Box Ci</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/09/17/spare-box-ci.html"/>
   <updated>2012-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/09/17/spare-box-ci</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have 2 employer provided computers.  One is a Mac Book Pro, the other is a Mac Pro.  I do my day to day development on the MBP because I want a smooth transition when I&amp;#39;m on the road.  I do this even though the desktop is a beast.  At home I use ShareMouse (a software KVM) so that the computers almost seem as one.  The desktop streams music from Pandora, has all the IM and email clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still wanted to leverage the desktop for my workflow.  The setup I have allows me to run CI unit tests against my local (laptop) git repo.  I&amp;#39;ll make changes, commit them and then the desktop will poll my laptop to see if there is anything new.  If there is something new then it does a full build and unit test.  I can continue doing other tasks on the laptop while the desktop is churning through our scala project (compiling scala code is resource intensive).  Then when I see that the build is in good shape I&amp;#39;ll do a push to our team GitHub Enterprise Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;On your laptop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell git it&amp;#39;s okay to export your project by touching this file: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;path-to-project&amp;gt;/.git/git-daemon-export-ok&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve up my local repo &lt;code&gt;git daemon --verbose --base-path=&amp;lt;path-to-project&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;On your desktop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Jenkins on the desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point desktop Jenkins to your git repo: &lt;code&gt;git://&amp;lt;your-network-ip&amp;gt;/.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scala Encoding Fun</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/03/15/scala-encoding-fun.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2012/03/15/scala-encoding-fun</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I pulled a toy Scala &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/demian0311/scalakata&quot;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; into Eclipse and saw this 
problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;IO error while decoding [file].scala with UTF-8 Please try specifying another one using the -encoding option
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://p5wscala.wordpress.com/tag/encoding/&quot;&gt;This guy&lt;/a&gt; didn&amp;#39;t have the exact solution but he got me pointed in the right direction.  The problem is that 
I must have copied in some non-UTF-8 characters into my source code.  At this point the Scala compiler
got confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a bunch of shell commands I did to fix the problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Figure out the character set of the file we&amp;#39;re having trouble with&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;~/code/scalakata&amp;gt;file -I ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala
./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala: text/x-java; charset=iso-8859-1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, the old iso-8859-1, that&amp;#39;s not what we want.  That&amp;#39;s what we use as the &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; encoding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Make a copy of the offending file UTF-8&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;~/code/scalakata&amp;gt;iconv -f iso-8859-1 -t utf-8 ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala &amp;gt; ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala.utf8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The diff command will show you what the offending line was&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;~/code/scalakata&amp;gt;diff ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala.utf8
134c134
&amp;lt;       // 4) Scala lets you multiply a string with a number?try out &amp;quot;crazy&amp;quot; * 3 in the REPL. What does this operation do? Where can you find it in Scaladoc?
---
&amp;gt;       // 4) Scala lets you multiply a string with a numberÑtry out &amp;quot;crazy&amp;quot; * 3 in the REPL. What does this operation do? Where can you find it in Scaladoc?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Now actually replace the old file&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;~/code/scalakata&amp;gt;mv ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala.utf8 ./src/test/scala/com/neidetcher/sfti/Chapter1Test.scala
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I was back in business.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Current Lifting Program</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2012/01/03/current-lifting-program.html"/>
   <updated>2012-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/fitness/2012/01/03/current-lifting-program</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple years I have gotten back into weight lifting.  It has
been great, I&amp;#39;m stronger than I was when I was in the Marines 20 years ago.
I&amp;#39;m nowhere near as fast though, maybe we&amp;#39;ll work on that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kettlebell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first got back into lifting I picked up the kettlebell at the 
recommendation of Bryan Noll.  This was a good place to start.  If I was
stranded on a desert island and could only have one piece of equipment it
would be a 53 pound kettlebell.  The simplicity of the device makes it
easy to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read Enter the Kettlebell, it&amp;#39;s a great resource to start.  It&amp;#39;s probably
enough just to buy yourself a kettlebell and watch some YouTub videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5x5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I wanted more body composition changes so I put together a
5x5 program for myself.  I was inspired by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://stronglifts.com/&quot;&gt;Stong Lifts e-book&lt;/a&gt;
but didn&amp;#39;t use his program.  He lays out a full-body system where every
day you work all muscle groups using old-school multi-joint barbell lifts.&lt;br&gt;
I think my body doesn&amp;#39;t recover quickly 
enough to lift a few times in a week.  I have always been that way even
though I respond well to lifting weights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a split routine that was push, pull and legs.  With a handful
of exercises that were all 5 sets of 5 reps.  I got great results with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5/3/1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 2011 I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jimwendler.com/&quot;&gt;Jim Wendlers 5/3/1 program&lt;/a&gt;.
5/3/1 is an undulating progression routine where you increase weights for 3 weeks
then take a week to do light work.  The 4 weeks you do the same gradual progression
but with 5-10 more pounds.  A program like 5/3/1 makes sense when you are no 
longer able to make linear progression of 5 pounds for a lift between workouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t hold a candle to the time under the bar and intelligence that Jim Wendler
has but after a couple cycles I quit doing 5/3/1 strictly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple reasons I didn&amp;#39;t like 5/3/1 strictly:
* my military press or overhead press is already in great shape and I don&amp;#39;t need 
  an entire day for shoulder work.
* I didn&amp;#39;t like the abscence of a day spent on back and pulling.  Although the
  5/3/1 deadlift day would probably be seen as a back day also.  5/3/1 also suggests
  doing pull-ups between all push movements, that would get you lots of time pulling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll probably give strict 5/3/1 another chance but for now this is what I&amp;#39;m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Modified 5/3/1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Leg&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5/3/1 squat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 leg curl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 leg extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x20 weighted hyper-extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 squat &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Press&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5/3/1 bench&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 military press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 dumbell press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 arnold press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 tricep press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pull&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 sets of pull ups, assisted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 bent row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 upright row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 db row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 curl machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x10 hang clean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--include:disqus.htm--&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Book Review My Job Went To India</title>
   <link href="http://neidetcher.com/2006/03/19/book-review-my-job-went-to-india.html"/>
   <updated>2006-03-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://neidetcher.com/2006/03/19/book-review-my-job-went-to-india</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;!--include:header.htm--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i bought the pdf version of the book.  if you haven&#39;t bought a pdf book from the pragmatic programmers they give you a customized book complete with your name on each page.  to do this processing it takes a few minutes before you can actually download your book.  your name in the book is to discourage you from throwing it up on some p2p system i&#39;m sure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;the book was great, i felt the same way as when i read the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;pragmatic programmer&lt;/span&gt;.  there were lots of moments where the author said things that seem obvious but it&#39;s always good to get validation.  even tho a lot of the information should be a given to anyone in the tech business the book serves as a kick in the pants to motivate you into change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;the book was well worth the price for the information that was new to me.  it wasn&#39;t so much new information but insightful things you can do to improve yourself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;here are some good points from the book:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;learn some obscure technologies: you can get a new perspective and differentiate yourself from the herd.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;learn your domain: if you&#39;re in telecom, learn your vertical, the coder ignorant of his business won&#39;t last long in the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;be a generalist: be a 1 man shop, networking, dba, coder, tester, architect&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;be a specialist: if you are a java developer &lt;b&gt;know java&lt;/b&gt;.  know how the classloader works, know serialization, know how to break the jvm, know garbage collection, know the libraries.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;don&#39;t become tiffany: remember her?  it&#39;s better to be like madonna, change with the times.  do an audit of your skills and where they are in the marketplace.  look for new trends.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;it&#39;s worth mentioning that the author has reverence for people in india.  he appreciates the culture and reminds us that they are intelligent as their stateside counterparts.  he reminds the reader that most indian workers are highly motivated to improve their standard of living.  the author also gives you insight into establishing a good relationship with distributed teams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;there&#39;s lots more wisdom in the book.  in the process of reading the book i&#39;ve made a checklist of things i want to do to improve myself professionally; books to read, tasks to do and things to learn.  ...yeah, i know i&#39;m so cool, seriously tho, that might be a good way to approach the book.  as i said, the book is worth the price especially if you&#39;re getting the pdf ($13).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0976694018?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=demian0311blo-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0976694018&quot;&gt;My Job Went to India: And All I Got Was This Lousy Book (Pragmatic Programmers)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=demian0311blo-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0976694018&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--include:disqus.htm--&gt;
&lt;!--include:footer.htm--&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
