<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demian Neidetcher</title>
    <description>I&#39;m a software engineer, primarily working with JVM languages and in the telecommunications domain.
</description>
    <link>http://neidetcher.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://neidetcher.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 11:23:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 11:23:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Review Smarter Faster Better</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not sure how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Smarter-Faster-Better-Productive-Business/dp/081299339X&quot;&gt;Smarter Faster Better&lt;/a&gt; by 
Charles Duhigg ended up on my Amazon wish list.  Perhaps it was because one of the first stories in the book deal
with Marines and new approaches they are taking to get recruits motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 7 chapters and they all go into something that&amp;#39;ll make you better in some manner.  The formula for each
chapter interleaves a couple stories, culminating in an actual concept that can improve your performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goal setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decision making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marine story deals with motivation and &lt;em&gt;locus of control&lt;/em&gt;.  The concept is that if you think control of your life is within 
you (as in you are responsible for your life) then you are likely to be more motivated.  That makes sense,
if you have a fatalistic attitude and life is more something that happens to you then you&amp;#39;re less likely to do
something about it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book also references lean and agile concepts borrowed from manufacturing and software engineering.  The stories
in that chapter came together particularly well.  An FBI software project was saved by using lean practices and
agents in the field used that software to solved a kidnapping.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same chapter that dealt with agile also talked about commitment culture with respect to management.  He describes
a big study during the dot-com era in Silicon Valley that evaluated different company cultures.  The results indicated that a 
&lt;em&gt;commitment culture&lt;/em&gt;, this is a company where the leadership puts the welfare of employees as a high priority, do
better more consistently than other scenarios.  The probably reason is low turnover means less intellectual
property walking out the door, less expense in training people.  Those teams also built up a lot of trust that
enabled collaboration and general healthy environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book was good.  Not all of the ideas are shocking but it&amp;#39;s good to firm up the concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/2016/08/09/book-review-smarter-faster-better.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/2016/08/09/book-review-smarter-faster-better.html</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Review How To Fail At Almost Everything</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Loss Leader Pays Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say with the current election season I am drawn to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.dilbert.com/&quot;&gt;writing of Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;.  He seems
to be one of the few people that has insight into the persuasion tactics that Trump employs.  Since 
he plugs his book in every blog post I finally relented and decided to read his book 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Fail-Almost-Everything-Still-ebook/dp/B00COOFBA4&quot;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is a lot of anecdotes in the life of Scott Adams.  It reads like a funny older dude trying to drop
knowledge bombs on someone younger than him.  He covers everything from being successful to what makes up a
good diet.  Some of his stories get a little drawn out like he goes to great lengths and takes many chapters
talking about some issues he had with his voice while speaking.  I&amp;#39;m not sure I took much away from that.  But
he&amp;#39;s a funny guy and it comes through in the book. He talks about a lot of his failures and how those 
ultimately led to him being a success.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;#39;ll know if you read his blog posts, Scott Adams has had some training in hypnosis and persuasion.  I 
have to say I get the impression I&amp;#39;m being gamed a bit when I read his writing.  All in all it&amp;#39;s a good book
if you like his style of writing then give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nuggets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like his assertion that goals are not good and that systems are a better approach.  He probably should just
use the word &lt;em&gt;habit&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;system&lt;/em&gt; but that doesn&amp;#39;t sound as cool.  When you set goals you find yourself
almost always being in a state of not meeting your goals.  Then &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you achieve your goal you set another one
and again, you&amp;#39;re in a state of being pre-goal.  It makes sense.  He prefers that you introduce habits into 
your life that will help you achieve goals that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like instead of some goal of getting in shape you should try to walk 5 times a week.  This reminds me of what
has become known as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&quot;&gt;Seinfeld approach&lt;/a&gt;.  The
idea is that if he would write new jokes every day then he thought he could get better.  So he bought a big
wall calendar and every day he wrote a joke he drew a red X on the calendar.  When he had a few days in a row
he would feel compelled to keep it going.  It&amp;#39;s a neat idea, instead of having a goal of &amp;quot;write lots of jokes&amp;quot;, 
he introduced a practice, a habit or a system that would move him towards that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I do like is his focus on fitness, nutrition and taking care of yourself.  Sometimes generosity prevents
us from taking care of ourselves.  He says you should be more selfish in that regard, that way you can do the
things you want to do, be with people who are important to you and be more generous in the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He points out that the more skills you have then the better off you are.  Often times it&amp;#39;s better to be &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; 
at multiple things than being the absolute best at one thing.  Like what if you&amp;#39;re good at programming and you&amp;#39;re
good at understanding human psychology.  Or what if you&amp;#39;re good at writing but also speaking.  You can understand
how the addition of those skills might help you find a niche better than being the absolute best at one skill.  It&amp;#39;s 
an interesting idea to consider.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In chapter 21, &lt;em&gt;The Math of Success&lt;/em&gt; he talks about skills that he thinks are important for most anyone.  It&amp;#39;s 
good to think about.  But you also have to know that this is one guy talking about what has worked for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;and many more...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, good book, easy read, I recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/2016/08/03/book-review-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/2016/08/03/book-review-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything.html</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Uberconf 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://uberconf.com&quot;&gt;UberConf&lt;/a&gt; 2016.  As always Jay Zimmerman puts on a great show.  As great
as UberConf is, it&amp;#39;s probably a conference you can get to every other year.  Lots of familiar speakers, they&amp;#39;re
all great.  I was surprised to see so few people I know in attendance.  Maybe people come to their senses and
get into management and I&amp;#39;m still slinging code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reactive Programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the all day workshop on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reactivemanifesto.org/&quot;&gt;reactive programming&lt;/a&gt; given 
by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agiledeveloper.com/&quot;&gt;Venkat&lt;/a&gt;.  It gave me a good basis for reactive programming. 
Venkat gave an entertaining presentation as always and he covered a lot of ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hangup would be that he focused on the idea of streams or data-flow computing.  He gave examples like stock data 
or telemetry data continually streaming into your application to be processed.  I&amp;#39;ve been coding 
professionally for almost 20 years and I have never been in a domain where that happens.  Honestly 
that kind of turned me off.  It&amp;#39;s not sexy but the fact is developers primarily create HTTP front-ends 
for either a persistence or some other back-end system.  From Venkat&amp;#39;s perspective if your app doesn&amp;#39;t
deal with streams of information then it&amp;#39;s not going to be of much use.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Spring and Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently have become re-interested in Spring.  I used Scala for a few years and then Groovy/ Grails.  I
forgot how useful all the Spring frameworks were.  They have kept up with things and a lot of the battle 
of being productive is just being aware of what&amp;#39;s out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of by &lt;a href=&quot;http://habuma.com/&quot;&gt;Craig Walls&lt;/a&gt;, they were great.  The theme of Craig&amp;#39;s 
talks were centered around &lt;em&gt;cloud native&lt;/em&gt;.  I like the idea, the point is that there are some 
new tools and concerns we&amp;#39;ll need when going to the cloud.  It doesn&amp;#39;t mean that all this is 
exclusive just to the cloud.  There was mention of &lt;a href=&quot;http://12factor.net/&quot;&gt;12 Factor Application&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;ve
gone through it before, seems like it&amp;#39;s something I need to re-visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He covered a lot of things about Spring.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/&quot;&gt;Spring&lt;/a&gt; is so huge and frankly they 
do a so-so job of organizing, documenting, deprecating and communicating best practices.  There&amp;#39;s 
just so much it&amp;#39;s probably very hard for them to keep a handle on it.  My point is that it&amp;#39;s great to 
hear someone speak that is up to speed on the best practices, how everything is positioned and really
just letting you know what&amp;#39;s out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also went to a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mattstine.com/&quot;&gt;Matt Stine&lt;/a&gt; talks about microservices.  In covering
microservices he also touched on Spring frameworks that help you.  Matt also covered reactive programming
in a more pragmatic way such that I could imagine using it with real work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Netflix&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nofluffjuststuff.com/conference/speaker/andrew_glover&quot;&gt;Andy Glover&lt;/a&gt; gave a keynote on 
Netflix.  I&amp;#39;m thankful for all the opensource software they have put out.  At my current work we
all looked like heroes just because we wired up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/Hystrix&quot;&gt;Hystrix circuit breakers&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That presentation went on about how great Netflix is, good on them, they&amp;#39;re doing amazing stuff.  But 
one thing that rubbed me wrong is how proud they are that they &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; hire senior engineers.  Is that a 
good thing if everyone just hires senior engineers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a 2 session Docker workshop.  There were a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of people in attendance and any time you&amp;#39;re doing
virtualization with more than 100 people things go off the rails quick.  So &lt;a href=&quot;https://juddsolutions.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Chrisopher Judd&lt;/a&gt; 
had his work cut out for him.   I was glad I attended, for whatever reason I couldn&amp;#39;t fit some Docker concepts
into my head just from reading but the sessions were useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More Take-Aways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;#39;s an interesting relationship with the cloud and microservices.  If you want to have microservices
you probably want to do cloud things to manage them even if you don&amp;#39;t use a cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spring and Netflix are doing great things, if you&amp;#39;re doing microservices or cloud stuff on the JVM you 
probably want to get familiar with the opensource tools they have available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to leverage Twitter&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://zipkin.io/&quot;&gt;Zipkin&lt;/a&gt; you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.spring.io/spring-cloud-sleuth/&quot;&gt;Spring Cloud Sleuth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least right now it&amp;#39;s too soon for me to poke around with Java9 module capabilities.  It&amp;#39;ll be interesting
when there is build system and tooling support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Netflix &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/eureka&quot;&gt;Eureka&lt;/a&gt; for service discovery.  This prevents you from hard-coding
URLs to services your application depends on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Netflix &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/zuul&quot;&gt;Zuul&lt;/a&gt; to dynamically route services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zuul could be used to host static assets &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; be a gateway for services.  If you do this then you don&amp;#39;t have to 
worry about cross origin request concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netflix has an interesting approach to load balancing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/ribbon&quot;&gt;Ribbon&lt;/a&gt; runs on 
the client, is made aware of services by Eureka and does a sort of load balancing in the client.  There isn&amp;#39;t
a load balancer that sits in front of services.  So, the client using Ribbon will round-robin or lay off of
poorly behaving services for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spring-cloud/spring-cloud-config&quot;&gt;Spring Cloud Config&lt;/a&gt; to manage configuration in 
your cloud applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-elasticsearch-logstash-and-kibana-elk-stack-on-ubuntu-14-04&quot;&gt;ELK&lt;/a&gt;
seems to be the approach for distributed, searchable logging.  Seems like a bunch of work to get going, we use Splunk 
at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/08/02/uberconf-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/08/02/uberconf-2016.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Review Lean Startup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous-Innovation/dp/0307887898&quot;&gt;Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt; for 
a while.  I didn&amp;#39;t know much about the book, you hear it recommended a lot and &lt;em&gt;lean&lt;/em&gt;, that&amp;#39;s good right?  The book is
good from my perspective as a software engineer, it provides some good perspective and a vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;#39;s main thesis is that a startup isn&amp;#39;t so much about &lt;em&gt;executing&lt;/em&gt; as it is about figuring out as quickly and
cheaply as possibly &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; the customer will actually want.  As an engineer we fall into the trap that if we build
this perfectly designed, scalable application using the latest technology then the effort is sure to be a winner.  The
author, Eric Ries, lays out how this isn&amp;#39;t helpful and gives lots of great examples to support his idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One concept I thought was great was the &lt;em&gt;concierge minimum viable product&lt;/em&gt;.  It doesn&amp;#39;t fit all startups but basically, 
if possible, you have humans do the work that computers would have done.  Like if it were Google Maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll likely recognize the scenarios he describes or imagine where a business would have done better had it applied
some of the things Lean Startup suggests.  One thing that was funny is that as I read the book I thought about the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hbo.com/silicon-valley&quot;&gt;HBO show Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt;.  As the last season wound down you would see them begin 
what will probably be a &lt;em&gt;zoom-in pivot&lt;/em&gt; towards a small feature they worked on in the hopes that focusing on that will 
support their venture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For the Software Engineer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is a good read for software engineers.  Lots of acknowledgement of good agile and lean practices.  There was
a good discussion of small batch sizes and why it&amp;#39;s good to release things in small amounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also favors a data-driven &lt;em&gt;metrics&lt;/em&gt; approach to understand if you are on the right track.  He goes into how tracking
the wrong data can be harmful, is sometimes goosed (again like in Silicon Valley) and too often the wrong data is left
to interpretation.  Lean Startup also talks about vanity metrics and gathering the right kind of metrics.  He favors
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cohort_analysis&quot;&gt;cohort analysis&lt;/a&gt; but doesn&amp;#39;t go into much detail about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/07/14/book-review-lean-startup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/07/14/book-review-lean-startup.html</guid>
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring Security Grails Plugin Gotcha</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Spring Security Grails Plugin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, our hero is doing a Grails application and wants some security in a brand new Grails 3.1.6 
application.  Good thing there&amp;#39;s a plugin for that and I can move onto the next thing right away.  Oh
 you sweet summer child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the dependency in &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot; data-lang=&quot;groovy&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dependencies&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;compile&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;org.grails.plugins:spring-security-core:3.1.1&#39;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I run the associated script to create the domain objects that are going to manage the
security like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;grails s2-quickstart com.yourapp User Role --groupClassName=RoleGroup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blissfully ignorant and following along with the documentation I charged forward.  Next up 
you quick data for development to associate the user to the role in &lt;code&gt;BootStrap.groovy&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot; data-lang=&quot;groovy&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dneidetcher&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;username:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;dneidetcher&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;firstName:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Demian&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;lastName:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Neidetcher&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;emailAddress:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;demian0311@gmail.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;password:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;foo&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;save&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;flush:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;UserRole&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dneidetcher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;adminRole&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;UserRole&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;withSession&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;flush&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;clear&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I apply my annotation on a controller so that I can allow access to it based on role:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot; data-lang=&quot;groovy&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;package&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;grails.plugin.springsecurity.annotation.Secured&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Secured&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;ROLE_ADMIN&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;UserController&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;scaffold&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identifying the Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you navigate to &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/user&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8080/user&lt;/a&gt; and you 
get &lt;em&gt;Sorry, you&amp;#39;re not authorized to view this page&lt;/em&gt; and nothing really more helpful than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that our sad story really began when we added this &lt;code&gt;--groupClassName=RoleGroup&lt;/code&gt; to 
the &lt;code&gt;s2-quickstart&lt;/code&gt; command we used to generate the code.  The net of it is that my &lt;code&gt;BootStrap.groovy&lt;/code&gt; code
that associated &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Role&lt;/code&gt; was insufficient.  The group stuff wants you to associate a &lt;code&gt;Group&lt;/code&gt; with
a &lt;code&gt;Role&lt;/code&gt; and then a &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; with that &lt;code&gt;Group&lt;/code&gt; to get anything done.  That&amp;#39;s all fine but it&amp;#39;s a layer of
indirection I don&amp;#39;t think I need.  It took me over 3 hours to figure this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Fix&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well in the first place I should have done this for my &lt;code&gt;s2-quickstart&lt;/code&gt; command.  That would have avoided the headache. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;grails s2-quickstart com.yourapp User Role 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in my case I wanted to attempt to back out of the mess so this is what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; you need to change this function to this implementation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot; data-lang=&quot;groovy&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Role&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getAuthorities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;UserRole&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;findAllByUser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)*.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;role&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;application.groovy&lt;/code&gt; you need to change this attribute to be false:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot; data-lang=&quot;groovy&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;grails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;plugin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;springsecurity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;useRoleGroups&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you need to remove all of the Spring Security Plugin generated domain objects that have the word &lt;code&gt;Group&lt;/code&gt; 
in them.  After that things worked as expected, Spring Security worked with my annotations.  So yeah, maybe 
not so much a &lt;em&gt;gotcha&lt;/em&gt; but me not knowing Spring Security well enough.  Regardless, onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/05/17/spring-security-grails-plugin-gotcha.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/05/17/spring-security-grails-plugin-gotcha.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>grails</category>
        
        <category>spring</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Videos From This Spring</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Denver 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past couple years I managed to get 2 snowboarding trips back to Denver.  This season I only got one.  Mike took his
daughter Chloe for lessons at Loveland so that&amp;#39;s where we went.  Visibility could&amp;#39;ve been better but I can&amp;#39;t complain. Work
flew a lot of people out so we could be in one place.  Enough of us were out such that our offices downtown Denver couldn&amp;#39;t
hold us all so we went over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.galvanize.com/&quot;&gt;Gavlanize&lt;/a&gt;.  It was great to see people, given the merger
not sure when or if I&amp;#39;ll get back there.  Holy cow Denver is growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WY_HC1weKYw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fat Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mardi Gras in Lafayette, Louisiana is more about parades, Cajun food and family.  I&amp;#39;m sure you could stir up some
trouble but it&amp;#39;s a tame affair for most. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zEQtZlEIXLw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/2016/05/12/videos-from-this-spring.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/2016/05/12/videos-from-this-spring.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strengths Finder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://timewarnercable.com&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; they had us take the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallupstrengthscenter.com&quot;&gt;Gallup StrengthsFinder&lt;/a&gt; test to see what our strengths 
are.  I figured they paid for it, why shouldn&amp;#39;t the whole world benefit from knowing what my 
strengths are according to Gallup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t imagine much will be done with this data but my co-workers and I compared our results 
and they were accurate.  Here they are in priority order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Learner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed I like to learn.  Programming is a great career for someone who likes to learn.  I like to 
be pragmatic about it, learning what I need to get something done and do the right things.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my personal life I see the same thing.  I cycle through different things to study, right now it&amp;#39;s 
amateur radio and a distant second of learning the guitar.  I don&amp;#39;t read fiction because I&amp;#39;d rather
be learning stuff, sure there are great rebuttals to that statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallup description says that sometimes for a learner the process is more significant than the
result.  I&amp;#39;d like to think that&amp;#39;s not the case with me.  I believe I am more pragmatic and that I
get amped up about applying what I learn to solve problems.  That&amp;#39;s when the payoff is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Strategic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah this is me too.  I think about the long-term results of decisions and wether or not we will come
to regret them.  I have a strong pull to share these views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Achiever&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallup copy explains this strength as needing continual success.  This one fits as well.  I know
that I sometimes say &amp;#39;we need a win&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;they need a W on the board&amp;#39;.  If I&amp;#39;m being honest with myself,
this isn&amp;#39;t all the time.  I need to be engaged and bought into what is happening.  I set goals for 
myself and I feel good about achieving them, peronsally and professionally.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also hear myself say &amp;#39;we need to make forward progress&amp;#39;.  So yeah this one is appropriate too.  When
I get my head wrapped around a problem I get a tight grip on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Responsibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this fits as well.  As with &amp;#39;achiever&amp;#39; I honestly need to be invested in the endeavor before I
attach that responsibility.  If something is out of my area or if there are other folks running with it
I do see myself not exercising this strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/2016/04/29/strengths-finder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/2016/04/29/strengths-finder.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Log The Stack In Java</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a method is executed and you&amp;#39;re just not sure how you got there.  You could bump up logging or
set a breakpoint but just logging the contents of the call stack is another good option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;logStack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;long&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currTime&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;currentTimeMillis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;info&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;logging stack at [{}]&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Arrays&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;stream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;currentThread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getStackTrace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;skip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ste&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ste&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;getClassName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;startsWith&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;com.exmple&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;forEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ste&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;info&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{} - ste: {}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currTime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ste&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We skip the first 2 elements of the stack because that contains where we called logStack from and
the current location.  It&amp;#39;s optional but I like to filter to just include classes that start with
our package name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/02/18/log-the-stack-in-java.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/programming/2016/02/18/log-the-stack-in-java.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>java</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entering Amateur Radio</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was in the Marines I remember a European NGO worker (I think 
he was with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icrc.org/&quot;&gt;ICRC&lt;/a&gt;) had a radio setup such that 
he could communicate around the world.  That seemed interesting at 
the time.  I don&amp;#39;t remember if he used it to conduct NGO business or
just communicate with people back home while he was in in remote parts 
of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently the local amateur radio club, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w5ddl.org/&quot;&gt;Acadiana Amateur Radio 
Association&lt;/a&gt;, was generous enough to conduct 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://theadvocate.com/news/acadiana/14385399-123/lafayette-class-helps-ham-radio-enthusiasts-learn-about-hobby-prepare-for-licensing&quot;&gt;free training&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lafayettesciencemuseum.org/&quot;&gt;Lafayette 
Science Museum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should also out myself as something of a prepper.  You get
accidental death and dismemberment insurance because there&amp;#39;s a remote
chance something bad will happen.  In the same sense you can have
interests that are fun but also prepare you if there is an emergency
at a local or national level.  I think amateur radio is one of those
interests.  Knowing what I know now about amateur radio I would want
a capable HAM in my fortified zombie-proof compound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go and I brought along my son Ryder.  The classes were
great, a good mix of general topics to get us engaged in HAM radio
and test preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting Certified&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FCC allows citizens to use portions of the radio spectrum for
personal use.  To prevent the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons&quot;&gt;tragedy of the commons&lt;/a&gt; the FCC requires
that citizens be licensed to use that spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 3 amateur radio licenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technician&lt;/strong&gt; lets you talk around town and possibly within the state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt; lets you talk nationally and possibly even all over the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra&lt;/strong&gt; frees up more of the spectrum to do more of the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Gordo&amp;#39;s Books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the class I read through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gordonwestradioschool.com/&quot;&gt;Gordon West&lt;/a&gt; books 
to prepare.  The books
are high quality, good paper, good color.  He has a good approach I think, he
co-locates the content with the questions and answers.  The dimensions of the
book make it easier to bring with you as you run errands so that if you have
a spare moment you can study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Technician-2014-18-Element-License-Preparation/dp/0945053797/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453213371&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=gordon+west&quot;&gt;Technician Class 2014-18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/General-Class-2015-2019-Gordon-West/dp/0945053827/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453213505&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=gordon+west&quot;&gt;General Class 2015-2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Studying and Practice Testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hamstudy.org/&quot;&gt;hamstudy.org&lt;/a&gt; was another invaluable resource to
prepare.  The only downside is that you need Internet connectivity to 
study.  The site seems to be smart about what it puts in front of you, 
as the learner your main mission is to chug through it until you&amp;#39;re at around
85% so that you can surely pass the tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned too late was that you can go into specific sections
of the test that you have trouble with.  This lets you focus on those questions
and see them more often.  I don&amp;#39;t think it&amp;#39;s the only way to go but perhaps it&amp;#39;s
good to mix it up like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;My Suggestions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#39;t peak too early, I did and I had to keep studying for a couple weeks to
retain.  Give yourself 2 or 3 weeks and go for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#39;t focus too much on the formulas.  I know the formulas and I get them but
I just memorized the answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit conversion (like from kHz to MHz) moves 3 decimal places, exclude answers that do not fit that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Except for decibels the math is always either multiplication or division, knowing
the right answer fits that will get you far.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always end transmissions with your call sign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always err on being safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always err on being nice. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mnemonics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To elaborate on the mnemonics, here are a couple that get me through 6 or so of the
answers.  If you&amp;#39;ve been through the questions you know how it helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;#39;s a duck in a field with a magnet in his mouth, he has a chain around his 
neck and it says &amp;quot;Henry&amp;quot;, he flies up and from the side his lips look like an inductor schematic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;#39;s an Arab guy named Farad in a field wearing a cap with a lightning bolt on it, the
top of his cap looks like a capacitor schematic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before their monthly meeting the local amateur radio club holds tests conducted by 
trained volunteers.  You can take as many tests as you would like for $15 but if you 
fail a test and want to re-take it you have to pay another $15.  I was able to take
both the technician and the general tests.  I did alright on the technician, for the 
general I was unsure but they told me I passed.  They asked if I wanted to go for
extra but I didn&amp;#39;t want to waste their time.  All the volunteers were awesome and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Call Sign&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week after testing I looked up my name with the FCC.  I was assigned the call sign
&lt;strong&gt;KG5KZM&lt;/strong&gt;.  Not too bad but I decided to apply for a vanity call sign right 
away.  Just like vanity plates for your car you can try to get a call sign of 
your choosing as long as it&amp;#39;s available.  It also has to be the right format for 
your license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You pick a dozen or so call signs you would like in priority order, wait 18 days and
find out what you got.  I chose a bunch of variations on X9DLN to have my initials.
Not very creative but seems easy to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;#39;s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to see if my son Ryder can pass for technician.  He&amp;#39;s slowly getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some hand-held radios that you&amp;#39;d use for local communication.  I&amp;#39;d like to get
into pack portable HF on battery and solar, lots to learn.  If I get up to speed I 
might look into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arrl.org/ares&quot;&gt;ARES&lt;/a&gt; to be helpful in emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/ham/2016/01/19/entering-amateur-radio.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/ham/2016/01/19/entering-amateur-radio.html</guid>
        
        <category>ham</category>
        
        
        <category>ham</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Checkstyle Suppressions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently focused on build tools that help keep code clean.  In &lt;a href=&quot;http://gradle.org/&quot;&gt;gradle&lt;/a&gt; I use
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pmd.github.io/&quot;&gt;PMD&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;findbugs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://checkstyle.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;checkstyle&lt;/a&gt;.  Probably about 50% of the time I check in code these
tools catch something bad I was attempting to do.  They have proven their worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I run into a problem though with beans where the equals that IntelliJ generates trips 
complexity warnings in checkstyle.  Running a &lt;code&gt;./gradlew check&lt;/code&gt; gives me an error 
that looks like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;:checkstyleMain
[ant:checkstyle] ./bar/src/main/java/com/example/foo/model/Thing.java:33:5: NPath Complexity is 48 (max allowed is 20).
:checkstyleMain FAILED
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I have refactored and teased apart this generated code but I finally came
to the conclusion that I wasn&amp;#39;t adding any value in that effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want is an unintrusive way to ignore that check for everything in a given path.
I stick my beans in a &lt;code&gt;model&lt;/code&gt; package so this isn&amp;#39;t too hard to suppress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Create a Suppressions File&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my project I have &lt;code&gt;./config/checkstyle/checkstyle.xml&lt;/code&gt; already.  I&amp;#39;m going to 
create a file in the same directory called &lt;code&gt;checkstyle-suppressions.xml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-xml&quot; data-lang=&quot;xml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE suppressions PUBLIC
        &quot;-//Puppy Crawl//DTD Suppressions 1.0//EN&quot;
        &quot;http://www.puppycrawl.com/dtds/suppressions_1_0.dtd&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;suppressions&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;suppress&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;checks=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;NPathComplexity&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;files=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;.*\/model\/.*&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/suppressions&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference the Suppressions File&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;code&gt;./config/checkstyle/checkstyle.xml&lt;/code&gt; I have this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-xml&quot; data-lang=&quot;xml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE module PUBLIC
        &quot;-//Puppy Crawl//DTD Check Configuration 1.3//EN&quot;
        &quot;http://www.puppycrawl.com/dtds/configuration_1_3.dtd&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Checker&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;SuppressionFilter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;property&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;file&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;value=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;./config/checkstyle/checkstyle-suppressions.xml&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/module&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://neidetcher.com/programming/2015/12/10/checkstyle-suppressions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://neidetcher.com/programming/2015/12/10/checkstyle-suppressions.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>java8</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
